--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
字幕翻译：伊甸园字幕组 后期处理：不死别姬
我父亲一生都恨律师
My father hated lawyers all his life.
我个人认为  他不算是个好人
He wasn't a great guy, my old man.
他酗酒  并且虐待我的母亲
He drank and beat up my mother.
他也殴打我
He beat me up, too.
要是你认为我要成为一个律师
So you might think I became a lawyer
只是为了气他
just to piss him off,
那你也许就错了
but you'd be wrong.
我之所以想成为一个律师
I've wanted to be a lawyer
是自从我读了有关民权律师
ever since I read about the civil rights lawyers
在五十和六十年代
in the fifties and sixties
为法律发掘出令人惊异的运用
and the amazing uses they found for the law.
他们做了许多人认为
They did what a lot of people thought
本来是不可能的事
was the impossible.
他们给了律师一个好名声
They gave lawyers a good name.
因此我进了法学院
And so I went to law school,
这确实激怒了我的父亲
and it did piss my father off,
不过他其实总是在发火
but he was pissed off anyway.
在我读大学的第一年  有一天他喝醉了
In my first year, he got drunk one day
从梯子上摔下来
and fell of a ladder
这发生在他干活的工厂里
manufactured by the company he worked for,
而他却不知道要先告谁
and he didn't know who to sue first.
大约两个月后他就因此去世了
Now, he died a couple months after that.
我喝干啦
I'm empty.
我的一些同学
Now, some of my classmates,
知道他们将从学校出去后直接
they knew they were going straight from school
进入顶级的律师事务所
into the top law firms,
主要依靠他们的家庭关系网
thanks mostly to their family connections.
而我所仅有的一个关系
Now, the only connections I had
是三年来在一个酒巴跑堂而建立起来的
were made in the places where I tended bar for 3 years
因为我得赚钱付我的学费
so I could pay my tuition.
当我踌躇满志
And while I still had plans
要让正义之光  照亮每一个黑暗角落
to shine the blazing light of justice into every dark corner,
我其实迫切需要的是一份工作
what I really needed right now was a job, and badly,
因为孟菲斯的律师  太多了
because there are too many lawyers in Memphis.
这座城市到处是他们的身影
This city's infested with them.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我不知道有什么能比这更令人苦恼了
I can't think of anything more embarrassing
就是告诉别人
than telling people
我是为伯鲁瑟斯通工作
I work for a guy like Bruiser Stone.
我是说  他是个律师  大家叫他伯鲁瑟
I mean, he's a lawyer, and they call him Bruiser.
这就是为什么我如此失望
That's how desperate I am.
当然
Sure.
把门关上
Shut the door.
不  不是那个  也不是那个
No, not that. Not that either.
当然
Sure.
就在我家吧
Let's make it my house.
好的
OK.
我真的同情这个可怜的FBI探员
I really pity the poor FBI technician
他非要想从交谈中
that's gonna have to extract the data
搞些资料出来
from that conversation.
律师的办公室里养着活生生的鲨鱼
Live sharks in a lawyer's office.
这是个玩笑  明白吗
It's a joke. Get it?
如此说来  普林斯
So, Prince,
这就是你向我提起过的法学院学生吗
is this the law student you were telling me about?
是  先生我刚在
Yes, sir. I just finished
孟菲斯州立大学读完三年级
my third year at Memphis state.
你能让他在这里工作吗
Couldn't you use him around here?
你看  我可以为他担保
Look, I'll vouch for him.
这孩子需要找份工作
The boy needs a job.
他在我们俱乐部的酒巴打工
He's tended bar at our clubs.
鲁迪  这儿会是你工作的好地方
This'll be a great place for you to work, Rudy.
这儿会是
This'll be...
你工作的好地方
A great place for you to work.
你可以看到真正的律师是怎么做的
You can see what real lawyers do.
但这里不提供带薪职位
Now, it ain't exactly a salaried position.
不算吗
It isn't?
我希望我的人  能自己挣出工资来
I expect my associates to pay for themselves--
自己创收
generate their own fees.
向我汇报
Talk to me.
那怎么运作呢
How exactly does that work?
嗯  鲁迪  你每月支取一千美金
Well, Rudy, you draw $1,000 a month,
另外你可以从你赚到的钱里抽取三分之一
and you get to keep 1/3 of all the fees that you generate.
要是你赚的比支取的多
Now, if you can't cover your draw
那到每个月底差额就算你欠我的
at the end of each month, you owe me the balance.
你听明白了吗
Do you understand?
我觉得挺公平  鲁迪
Sounds fair to me, Rudy.
这是个不易接受的交易  的确如此
That's a hell of a deal, really.
但这么做你能挣很多钱
You can make a lot of money this way.
嗯嗯
Mmm...
让我来告诉你  鲁迪
I'll tell you something, Rudy.
这是我唯一的经营方式
That's the only way I operate.
我会让你接手很多好案子
And I'll get you a lot of good cases.
我手里有案子
I have cases.
哦嗯
Uh...
我现在手上有两个案子
I have 2 cases right now.
一个是办遗嘱
One is a will
我替一个老妇人起草遗嘱
that I'm drafting for an old woman.
她很富有  值好几百万
She's loaded, too. She's worth millions.
而另一个案子
And then I have this other case.
是个保险案子
It's an insurance case.
巨大福利公司  听说过么
Great Benefit. You heard of 'em.
你有委托人的签字吗
You got these clients signed?
我现在正要去找他们
I'm on my way to see 'em right now,
他们也很愿意听我的意见
and they'll listen to me, too.
我在法律工作室帮过他们的忙
I helped 'em over at a law workshop.
很好  我会让你去和我的一个同事
All right, I'm gonna have you talk
狄克谢佛来尔谈谈
to an associate of mine, Deck Schifflet.
他常与那些大保险公司打交道
He used to work with these big insurance companies.
他负责所有高级别的案件
He handles all the high-powered stuff around here.
嘿  狄克
Hey, deck!
狄克
Deck!
该死的
Damn it.
你建立了那些案子的档案了吗
You got the paperwork on this stuff?
在我的车上
In my car.
很好
Good.
嘿  帅哥
Hey, good lookin'
这是狄克谢佛来尔
this is Deck Schifflet.
这家伙会带你上路
This man will get you plugged in.
我想让你做的是
What I want you to do,
立案起诉这个巨大福利保险公司
I want you to draw up a lawsuit against this Great Benefit,
并署上我的名字
and you put my name on it.
我们今天就建立档案
We're gonna file it today.
谢谢你
Thank you.
鲁迪  你会学到很多东西
Rudy, you're gonna learn a lot.
鲁迪  我很高兴你到这儿来
Rudy, I'm glad you came here.
你做了个很好的选择  孩子
You're making good choices already, son.
不错  那么  谢谢你
All right, well, thank you.
好的  谢谢你
OK, thank you.
出去的时候把门带上  好吗
Close the door on your way out now, OK?
律师事务所  要帮忙么
Law offices. May I help you?
这是个办公室  有人在里面
This is an office, there's people in it.
你就别用它  太挤了
You...
这里是厕所
This is the bathroom.
等一会儿
Just a minute.
对不起
Sorry.
那么  你是他的的同事吗
So, are you an associate here?
算是吧  不是正式的
Sort of. Not really.
确凿说来我还不算个律师
I'm actually not a lawyer yet.
伯鲁瑟一般要求我
Bruiser usually asks me
审查那些牵涉保险的案子
to review the insurance cases when they come in.
我曾经在保险公司工作
I used to work for specific mutual insurance company.
干厌了就进了法学院
I got sick of that. I went to law school.
那么  你什么时候从法学院毕业的
Well, when did you finish law school?
五年前
5 years ago.
瞧  我在律师执照考试上
See, I'm having a little trouble
有那么点儿小麻烦
with the bar exam.
我考了六次
I sat for it 6 times.
听到这些真让我感到遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
是啊  你什么时候参加执照考试
Yeah. When do you take yours?
我差不多三周后就要考了
I take it in, like, 3 weeks.
噢  是啊
Oh, yeah.
这真那么难吗
It's that hard?
我要说  相当地难
Pretty rough, I'll say.
我一年前考过
I took it a year ago.
我想  我再也不去考了
I don't think I'm gonna take it again.
随它去吧  这里是伯鲁瑟的法律图书室
Anyway, this is Bruiser's law library.
要是你从冰箱里拿任何东西
If you want to get anything
或者你要用这个冰箱
out of the fridge or use the fridge,
你可以在你的东西上写上你的名字
you can put your name on stuff.
不过他们照样会吃了它  把这个放进去
They'll eat it anyway. Put that in for me.
噢  这只是米饭罢了  这是什么玩意儿  黛茜
Aw, it's only rice. What the hell. Daisy.
哎
Yeah.
我们把这儿搞的很糟  清理一下啊
We made a mess here. Get that up, huh?
当然  狄克
Sure, deck.
随它去吧
Anyway...
等等  你上法庭的时候怎么办
So wait, what happens when you have to go to court?
老实说  我是很少单独出庭的
I've actually gone a few times myself.
所以至今还没被抓住过
I haven't gotten caught.
这里有这么多律师
There's so many lawyers here,
我们不太可能会引起注意
it's impossible to keep up with us.
伯鲁瑟拥有这一切
Bruiser owns all this.
噢  真不错哦
Oh. Nice.
你真不能称其为律师事务所
You can't call it a firm exactly.
每个人都只是为了自己
It's every man for himself.
你会学到的
You'll learn.
什么  你是在搬家吗
What, are you moving?
被赶出来了
Evicted.
这是保险单
Here's the policy.
不错
Yeah.
你觉的怎么样
What do you think?
嗯  这真是最烂的保单
Well, this is the scratch-and-sniff armpit of the industry.
他们拒付的理由是什么
What are their grounds for denial?
噢  全部拒付
Oh, well, everything.
先在不符合理赔规定
They first denied it just on principle,
然后他们说白血病
and then they said that leukemia
是在投保之前就有的
was a pre-existing condition,
接着又说
and then they said
白血病根本就不在本保单范围内
leukemia wasn't covered in the policy.
我这里有七封信
I got 7 letters here.
保费都交全了么
Have all the premiums been paid?
根据勃拉克女士的说法
According to Miss Black,
每一项保费她都付过了
she paid every single one of them.
这些个杂种
The bastards.
这是典型的保险诈骗
This is a typical debit insurance scam.
黑人们称这为街头险
The Blacks call it street-surance.
我该怎么办
So what do I do?
你签字接办  所有的都签
You sign 'em up. Sign 'em all up.
然后交给简李曼斯通事务所
To J. Lyman Stone.
好吧
All right.
这就对了  我会帮你
Yeah. I'll help you on this one.
好的  那么  谢谢  十分感谢
All right. Well, thank you. I appreciate it.
没什么比搞定保险公司
There's nothing more thrilling
更令人激动的事了
than nailing an insurance company.
嗨  勃拉克女士  我是鲁迪拜勒
Hi, Ms. Black. It's Rudy Baylor.
还记得吗  我在处理你控告
Remember? I'm handling your case
巨大福利保险公司的案子
against Great Benefit.
对  快请进来
Well, come in.
请进  很抱歉  那些疯狗
Come in. I'm sorry about them crazy dogs.
噢  那没什么
Oh, that's OK.
我还以为你是  耶和华听证会的教士呢
I thought you was a Jehovah’s witness.
伯迪在哪儿
Where's Buddy?
他在外面车里
He's out in the car.
他要去哪儿
Where's he going?
他哪儿都不去
Buddy isn't going nowhere.
他的脑袋不太对劲儿  是战争创伤
He ain't right in the head. War injury.
在朝鲜留下的  知道机场的金属探测器吧
Korea. You know them metal detectors at the airport?
他就是脱光了过安检
He can walk through one buck naked,
警铃都会响个不停
and the thing would go off.
他的脑袋里还留着块弹片
He's got a plate in his head.
哦哦
Oh.
这真是可怕
That's awful.
丹尼雷还好吗
How's Donny Ray?
嗯  时好时坏的
Well, good days and bad.
脑袋里留着块弹片
"Plate in head."
你要见他吗
You want to meet him?
也许等会儿吧
Maybe later.
嗯  现在嗯
Mmm, now...
巨大福利保险公司  第一次拒赔是在去年八月
Great Benefit first denied your claim last August
当丹尼雷被确诊之后
when Donny Ray was diagnosed.
为什么直到现在  你们才向律师咨询
Why'd y'all wait till now to consult a lawyer?
我猜是愚蠢吧
Stupid, I guess.
我只是不断地给他们写信
I just kept writing 'em,
而他们也不断地给我回信
and they kept writing me back,
哪  这是最后收到的一封
and this here is the latest one.
亲爱的  勃拉克女士
"Dear Mrs. Black,
前面七次
"on 7 prior occasions
本公司已经书面拒绝了你的索赔要求
"this company had denied your claim in writing.
现在我们第八次也是最后一次  拒绝赔偿
"We now deny it for the eighth and final time.
你一定是很愚蠢  很愚蠢  相当的愚蠢
You must be stupid, stupid, stupid."
真诚地  艾沃特鲁富肯  理赔部副总经理
"Sincerely, Everett Lufkin, Vice President of Claims."
真令人难以置信
I don't believe this.
你就是那位律师
You're the lawyer.
我妈夸过你好多次
Mom says nice things about you.
她说你会控告巨大福利保险公司的混蛋
She says you're suing those bastards over at Great Benefit.
让他们赔钱  是不是
Gonna make 'em pay, huh?
对  是这样
That's right.
是这样的
嗨  妈妈
Hi, mama.
嗨  亲爱的
Hi, honey.
好吧  在我们建立索赔档案之前
Well, before we can file a claim,
我需要你们三个人的签字
I need all 3 of you to sign this.
爸爸进来么
Is daddy coming in?
唉  他说会进来的
Well, he said he wasn't.
他有时候进来
Some days he comes in,
有时候又不进来
and some days he don't.
好吧  这是合同
Well, this is a contract.
上面写了些什么
What's in it?
噢  很普通
Oh, the usual.
只是些格式条款
It's standard language.
总的来说就是
It basically says
你们将请我们做为代理人
that y'all hire us to be your attorneys,
我们将接手处理你们的案子
and we take care of the case for you.
并负担所有可能的开销
We handle any expenses that we might have,
然后我们从赔偿款中抽取三分之一作为佣金
and then we get 1/3 of any recovery.
好吧  可就这么几句话  干嘛要写两页纸
OK...
别点了
don't light that.
怪不得我要死了
No wonder I'm dying.
我们三个人都必须签吗
And all 3 of us have to sign it?
是的  夫人  都得签  签在你们名字旁边
Yes, ma'am, all 3. Just where your name is.
他说他不进来
He said he wasn't coming in.
拿枝笔去外面
Take the pen and go out there
让他去签下
and make him sign the damn thing.
我想我只能这么办了
I guess I could.
喂  伯迪
Now, Buddy,
你得在文件上签个字
you gotta sign this paper
这样丹尼雷就可以做手术了
so Donny Ray can get that operation he needs,
别找麻烦
and I don't want no trouble out of you.
把这可恶的酒瓶子给我
I'll take that damn bottle
我要把它扔到大街上去
and throw it across union street.
现在  在这签字  快点  快点儿
Now sign the damn thing. Come on, hurry up.
我知道你一定以为他们都疯了
I know you must think they're crazy.
他们都是很好的人
They're nice folks.
嗨  哥们儿
Hey, man.
嗨  你留鼻血了
Hey, your nose is bleeding.
勃拉克女士
Mrs. Black!
把头仰起来
Hold your head up.
勃拉克女士
Mrs. Black!
没什么我来弄
It's OK. I got it.
他在流鼻血
He's bleeding.
把头仰起来  仰起来
Put your head back. Put your head back.
快点儿  仰起头来
Come on, put it back.
啊  亲爱的  没什么  一切都会好的
Oh, sweetie, OK, it'll be all right.
我自己来
I got it.
让我自己来
都会好的  都会好的
OK, OK.
好啦  我捂住了
OK, I got it.
你一定会好起来的
You're gonna be all right.
文件在哪里
Where's the paper?
丹尼雷  你不能稍稍歇一歇吗
Donny Ray, why don't you just rest a little bit?
你可以等一会儿的
You can wait.
你不用着急
You don't have to do this now.
不  不  我想现在就做
No, no. I want to do this now.
好吧
OK.
对  对  你能做到
All right, all right, you can do it.
请继续
Go ahead.
就好了
You're doing it.
啊  柏蒂女士  这是鲁迪拜勒嗯
Uh, Miss Birdie, it's Rudy Baylor.
什么
What?
你是谁
Who is it?
这是鲁迪拜勒
It's Rudy Baylor.
噢哦
Oh.
我们在孟菲斯法律工作室见过
We met at the law workshop at Memphis state.
噢  对了  噢  请进  快请进
Oh, yes. Oh, come in, come in.
多谢  多谢
Thank you, thank you.
不错  很不错
Yeah! great!
柏蒂女士  我想跟您谈谈遗嘱的事情
Miss Birdie, I wanted to talk to you about your will.
把我的孩子们从我的遗嘱里剔出去
Cut my children out of my will.
剔除  剔除  剔除
Cut, cut, cut.
剔除  剔除  剔除  我知道了
Cut, cut, cut. I know.
我昨晚上没睡好
I had trouble sleeping last night
原因是我一直在担心您的财产
'cause I was worried about your estate.
现在  如果您大意了  柏蒂女士
Now, if you're not careful, Miss Birdie,
政府就会从中抽取相当大的份额
the government is just gonna get a big chunk of this.
其实  很多税款是可以避免支付的
Now, a lot of these taxes can be avoided
只要仔细制订一下财产分配计划
with a little bit of careful estate planning.
噢  全都是废话
Oh, that legal gobbledygook.
是不是想把你的名字
I suppose you want your name
写进我的遗嘱里去
in the will somewhere.
当然不是  夫人
Of course not.
律师们总是想把他们的名字写进我的遗嘱
Lawyers are always wanting their names in my wills.
不  夫人  律师和律师是不一样的
No, ma'am. Well, there are all kinds of lawyers.
为了安排您的财产  我需要您告诉我
What I do need from you is, for purposes of estate planning,
钱是存在哪里的
I do need to know where the money is.
是债券  股票还是现金
Is it in bonds or stocks or cash?
哎  鲁迪  别那么急  不要那么急嘛
Now, Rudy, not so fast, not so fast.
好吧  夫人  那先不管在哪儿  反正有这笔钱
OK, ma'am. So we have this money somewhere.
我们将把它留给谁呢
Who are we gonna leave it to?
好吧
Well,
我希望把所有的钱留给
I want it all to go
肯尼思钱德勒  教士
to the reverend Kenneth Chandler.
你知道这个人吗
Do you know him?
他最近老是出现在达拉斯的电视里
He's on television all the time now out of Dallas.
他一头的灰白卷发  老得早了点
Got this curly gray hair premature,
他根本不会想到
and he wouldn't dream
会得到这笔钱的  你知道吗
of touching it up, you know?
我希望他拿到这笔钱
I want him to have the money.
对不起  柏蒂女士  嗯
Forgive me, Miss Birdie. Um...
什么
What?
我只是有一个很实际的问题
I just have a real problem
起草这么一个遗嘱或契约
drafting a will or any instrument
要把家庭成员都剔除出去
that's gonna cut out family
反而
and that's gonna replace it
把大部分财产
and convey the bulk of this estate
给一个电视台的人物
to a TV personality.
啊  他是上帝的使者
Well, he's a man of God.
我感觉到了
I realize that.
我懂
I know.
有没有别的方法把这件事情
Is there any way we could attack this in more of a--
有必要把所有的一切都给他吗
do you have to give him everything?
能不能  比如说  给他25%
Could it be more, say, 25%
他的开销很大
he's got a lot of overhead,
他的零件也已经老了
and his jet is getting old.
零件已经老了
His jet is getting old?
这样  鲁迪  我希望请你只是
Now, Rudy, I want you to just please
按照我要求的去起草
draw it up the way I ask
然后拿回来让我过目  怎么样
and bring it back to me so I can review it, all right?
这是强盗小时候还招人喜欢时的照片
Here's the hustlers when they were still young and sweet.
剔除  剔除  剔除
Cut, cut, cut.
你会回来的  是不是
You come back now, huh?
哦  我会  我会的
Oh, I will, I will.
谢谢您
Thank you.
不客气  谢谢你
No. Thank you.
后院是个小公寓吗
Is that a little apartment back there?
以前是的
Used to be.
你觉得我的花园怎么样
What do you think about my garden?
啊  这是个很漂亮的花园
Oh, that's a fine-looking garden.
您自己当园丁吗
Do you do all the work on this yourself?
大部分是
Most of it.
我请了一个男孩子  每周替我剪一次草
I pay a young boy to cut the grass for me once a week.
我付三十美金  你信吗
$30. Can you believe it?
以前是五美金的
Used to be 5.
噢  我不知道您想不想
Well, I don't suppose you'd be interested
出租这个地方  愿意么
in renting this place out now, would you?
我可付不起太多租金
I couldn't afford much, though.
我会给你个好价钱的
I could let you have it quite reasonably
只要你能帮我干点杂货
if you'd assist me with a few chores around the place.
当然  当然可以
Sure, sure.
也就是除除草之类的
Perhaps a little weed pulling now and then.
当然  我是除草专家
Sure. Weed pulling's my specialty.
我常来医院
Go to hospitals all the time.
伯鲁瑟和各行都有联系
Bruiser has contacts down at the main precinct,
他的那些发小们
guys he grew up with.
每天早上都会向他提供事故报告
They feed him accident reports every morning.
我可以问你点儿事吗
Can I ask you something?
当然
Sure.
到底伯鲁瑟想让我做什么
What does Bruiser expect me to do?
发掘案子  找受害人
Get the case. You find the victims.
让他们委托  简李曼斯通律师事务所  替他们打官司
You sign 'em up to the law firm of J. Lyman Stone.
把案子集中起来
Put the case together.
这么说我得去征求别人
So I should solicit?
在法学院他们是怎么教你的
What did they teach you in law school?
嗯  他们并没有教我追着救护车跑
Well, they didn't teach me how to chase ambulances.
好吧  你最好快点儿学会  否则就要挨饿了
Well, you better learn quick, or you're gonna starve.
你只要预约一个门诊
All you have to do is ask for a doctor
我们现在就可以为您登记  当然
and we can admit you right here. Sure.
好漂亮的花
Nice flowers.
多谢
Thanks.
维廉姆
William.
狄克  你好吗
How you doing, deck?
挺好  去346病房
All right. 346.
威尔斯大夫
Dr. Wells.
早上好
Morning.
你好吗  有幸见到你
How are you? Good to see you.
别整的像个律师
don't act like a lawyer.
哼  请勿入内嗯
Hmm. "Do not enter."
你好吗  麦克肯兹先生
How you doing, Mr. McKenzie?
我的化验怎么样啦
How are my tests?
该死  钓错鱼了
Gall bladder. Wrong fish.
万蓝德尔先生
Mr. Van Landel.
下午好  万蓝德尔先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Van Landel.
能听见我说话吗  万蓝德尔先生
Can you hear me, Mr. Van Landel?
嗨
Hi.
你是谁啊
Who are you?
我是狄克谢佛来尔  救难的律师
I'm Deck Schifflet, para-lawyer.
没有
No.
很好  不要和他们交谈
Good. don't talk to 'em
因为他们只是要勒索你
because they're just out to screw you.
你有没有私人律师
Do you have a lawyer?
没有
No.
我的律师事务所处理的车祸案子
My firm handles more car wrecks
在孟菲斯是最多的
than anybody in Memphis.
保险公司见了我们就怕
Insurance companies are terrified of us,
而且我们不收一分钱
and we don't charge a dime.
你能不能等我太太来了再说
Can you wait till my wife gets back?
你太太  万先生
Your wife, Mr. van-- Aah!
对不起
Sorry.
真对不起  万蓝德尔先生
I'm very sorry, Mr. Van Landel.
非常抱歉
Very sorry.
你太太在哪儿  万蓝德尔先生
Where is your wife, Mr. Van Landel?
她稍等一会儿就会回来
She'll be back in a little while.
好的  我想在我的办公室和她谈谈
Well, I'm gonna have to talk to her down in my office
因为我需要了解很多情况
because there's a ton of information that I need.
在这上面签个字吧
Just sign right there.
记住  除了你的大夫之外
Remember, don't talk to anybody
别与任何人交谈
except your doctor.
来找你的人会有很多的
There are gonna be people coming at you from every direction
向你提供解决方案
offering you settlements.
我不希望你在任何情况下
I do not want you under any circumstances
在我没有审查之前  签署任何文件
to sign anything without me reviewing it first.
听明白了没  我的电话号码  就写在名片上
Understand? My number is on this card.
你24小时都可以找我
You can call me 24 hours a day.
鲁迪拜勒先生的电话号码印在反面
Mr. Rudy Baylor's number is on the back.
你也可以在任何时候找他  好吗
You can call that number for him any time, OK?
你还有什么疑问吗
Do you have any questions?
没有
No.
很好  我们会帮你讨回一大笔钱的
Good. We're gonna get you a bunch of money.
我们走吧
Let's go.
对你的腿  我真是非常抱歉
I'm real sorry about your leg.
请你让我一个人清静一下
I'd like to be alone please.
这就是怎么去做交易的
And that is how it's done.
小菜一碟啦
Piece of cake.
要是遇到个家伙有自己的律师呢
What if the guy had a lawyer?
我们没做什么承诺
We came with nothing.
如果出于某种原因  把我们赶出门
If he'd have thrown us out of his room
我们也没失去什么吧
for whatever reason, what have we lost?
失去点儿做人的尊严
A little dignity.
也许是自尊
Maybe a little self-respect.
你瞧
You see...
鲁迪  在法学院里
In law school, Rudy,
他们并不教你想学的
they don't teach you what you need to know.
那里只有理论  玄虚的概念
It's all theories and lofty notions
再加上大本的道德规范
and big fat ethics books.
道德又有什么不对
What's wrong with ethics?
我猜  没什么不对吧
Nothing, I guess.
我的意思是  我相信一个律师
I mean, I believe a lawyer
必须为他的委托人去战斗
should fight for his client,
防止钱财被盗去
refrain from stealing money.
并且尽量不骗人
And try not to lie.
你知道的  这是最基本的
You know, the basics.
这样追着救护车找客户  太卑鄙了
That was blatant ambulance chasing.
没错儿  可谁在乎呢
Right, but who cares?
遍地都是律师
There's a lot of lawyers out there.
这就是市场  这就是竞争
It's a marketplace. It's a competition.
法学院没教你的东西  可能会让你受伤的
What they don't teach you in law school can get you hurt.
你怎么判断律师是否在说谎
How do you know when a lawyer is lying?
他开口就是在说谎
His lips are moving.
律师和妓女有什么区别
What's the difference between a hooker and a lawyer?
至少妓女在你死后  就不会再缠着你了
A hooker will stop screwing you after you're dead.
大家都喜欢听有关律师的笑话
Everybody loves lawyer jokes,
律师自己就特别喜欢
especially lawyers.
他们甚至以此为荣
They're even sort of proud of 'em.
谁知道为什么会这样的
Why do you suppose that is?
第三方将辩护
A third party is no different.
所以控方也可以利用这一点
He may also be used by the plaintiff
去引进第三方证人
to bring in a third party.
你这是在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
噢  我在学习
Oh, I'm studying.
我觉得学习该占用自己的时间
I thought we was gonna study on our own time.
我知道  伯鲁瑟  可是你瞧  先生
I know, Bruiser, but look, man,
下个礼拜要考律师执照了  对不
the bar exam is next week, all right?
就是下个礼拜
It is next week.
我有点儿担心  先生
I'm scared, man.
嗨  鲁迪  瞧  你想学习
Hey, Rudy, look, you want to study,
为什么不能跑到医院去学
why don't you run over to the hospital
跟狄克学习
and study with deck?
我不想从那方面学
I'm not gonna study with--
我不想跟着狄克学
I'm not gonna study with deck.
不错  我这里有个警察的报告
Yeah, I got a police report here.
我们能做这个受害人的代理人吗  雷科女士
Do we represent her, this victim here?
嗯  还没有
Well, not yet.
那为什么你不能跑到医院去看看
Why don't you run down to the hospital and check it out?
也许你能得到她的委托
Maybe you could sign her up.
你能替我弄点饮料来吗
Would you get me a soda?
当然  亲爱的
Sure, darling.
你要的饮料来了
Here you go.
这些伤都是从哪儿来的
Where did this all come from?
你想告诉他们
Are you gonna tell them where
这些伤是怎么来的吗
all this stuff came from?
在我注视他们那一刻
I know what's going on
我知道这事是怎么发生的
the second I lay eyes on them.
就如同我十岁大时
Like I'm 10 years old,
我父亲在卧室里哭
my father crying in the bedroom,
我母亲满脸是血
my mother sitting at the kitchen table
坐在餐桌旁
with blood all over her face
告诉我说爸爸很懊悔
telling me that daddy's sorry,
并保证以后再不这样做了
and he's never gonna do it again.
老天爷
Jeez!
你只要对我说是
Just tell me yes!
为什么你要这样对我
Why are you doing this to me?
和你在一起  总是这样
It's always the same with you!
你让我发疯
You make me so crazy!
凯丽雷科  三天前
Kelly Riker was admitted
就被送到圣彼德医院了
to St. Peter's hospital 3 days ago,
我想强调一下  是在半夜里
at midnight, I might add,
带着各式各样的伤
with assorted injuries.
警察在小房间的沙发上发现了她
The cops found her lying on the sofa in the den,
赤身裸体裹着条毯子  几乎被打死了
beat to hell, wrapped in a blanket, naked.
克利夫雷科
Cliff Riker,
她的丈夫  显然是喝醉了酒
her spouse, was obviously intoxicated,
情绪激动
highly agitated,
一开始居然想用打老婆的东西  殴打警察
and initially wanted to dish out to the cops what he was giving his wife.
她是被
Which was, by the way,
一根铝合金棒球棒  狠揍了一顿
a severe beating with an aluminum baseball bat.
这是他惯用的凶器
Evidently his weapon of choice.
让我们来讨论一下柏蒂女士的百万家产
Let's talk about Miss Birdie's millions.
不  我想讨论克利夫的案子
No, I want to talk about Cliff.
我想讨论克利夫身上发生了些什么
I want to talk about what happened to Cliff.
他只被关了一晚上
He spent the night in jail.
他家里把他保释了出来
His family bailed him out.
哦  不错嗯
Uh, all right.
考林  简尼思  伯德松
Colleen Janice Birdsong.
她的确是从第二个丈夫手里
She did indeed inherit a couple of million bucks
继承了几百万遗产
from her late second husband.
可是扣除律师费  失败的信托投资
But lawyers, bad trust department investments,
以及税金  他的财产已经所剩无几
and the IRS totally devoured the estate.
大概只剩四万美金
All except for about $40,000,
恐怕柏蒂女士  把它们都塞进了床垫里
which Miss Birdie probably tucked in her mattress
如我们所知
for all we know.
对不起
Sorry.
你是我的阳光
♪ you are my sunshine ♪
我唯一的阳光
♪ My only sunshine ♪
你令我快乐
♪ You make me happy ♪
当天空灰濛濛的时候
♪ When skies are gray ♪
哒 哒...
♪ Da da da da da ♪
不要夺走我的阳光
♪ Do not take my sunshine away ♪
噢  早上好啊  鲁迪
Oh, good morning, Rudy.
这是不是可爱的一天啊
Isn't it a lovely day?
噢  是的  天气真美
Oh, yeah, it's-- it's beautiful.
噢  铺草坪的垫土来了
Oh, here's my mulch.
正好  那边点儿  靠那边点儿
That's right. There, there.
就在这儿  对
Right there. Yes.
停  停下
Stop it, stop it.
不错  就直接卸在这儿吧
All right. Just put it right there now.
我的园丁会来取的
My yard boy will get it.
就卸在这儿
Just right down there.
好大一堆啊
Isn't that a fine bunch of mulch?
对不起
Excuse me.
我并非多管闲事  但是
I'm not one to meddle, but...
你没什么吧
Are you all right?
你是不是痛啦
Are you in pain?
不是
No.
不过还是多谢了
But thanks.
嗯  好吧  我就站这儿
OK, well, I'm right up here.
我只不过在那边准备律师执照考试
I'm just studying for the bar exam,
要是你有什么事的话
so if you need anything,
就招呼我一声
just holler at me.
好的
OK.
不管什么事  好吗
Anything. All right?
我会为你做的
I'll get it for you.
我叫鲁迪拜勒
My name is Rudy Baylor.
凯丽雷科  很高兴与你相识
Kelly Riker. Nice to meet you.
凯丽  能认识你很高兴
Kelly, it's nice to meet you, too.
为什么你不坐下来
Why don't you sit down?
去搬个椅子坐下来嘛
Go ahead. Take a seat.
你在那个学校念书
What school do you go to?
我进过奥斯汀匹艾
I went to Austin Peay
后来就进了孟菲斯州立大学的法学院
and then law school at Memphis state.
我一直想进大学
I always wanted to go to college,
但却一直也没成功
but it didn't work out.
真的吗
Did you?
是啊  我一直以为我会进的
Yeah. I always thought I'd go,
可就是没成功
but it didn't work out.
你想成为一个什么样的律师
What kind of lawyer do you want to be?
嗯  我喜欢庭审工作  所以嘛
Well, I enjoy trial work, so, uh...
我喜欢整天都待在法庭上
I'd like to spend my days in the courtroom.
为罪犯辩护吗
Defending criminals?
也许  也许吧
Maybe. Maybe.
他们也需要有人辩护
They're entitled to a good defense.
在法庭上他们有这个权力
They have a right to their day in court.
那杀人犯呢
Murderers?
大多数杀人犯  雇不起私人律师
Most murderers can't afford a private lawyer.
强奸犯
Rapists and...
和侵害儿童的罪犯呢
Child molesters?
不
No.
那么殴打妻子的男人呢
Men who beat their wives?
刑事案件有其特殊性
Criminal work is a real rare specialty.
我更愿意做嗯
Mmm, I'll probably be doing more, uh...
民事诉讼
Civil litigation.
就像诉讼和调查
Like lawsuits and stuff.
-对  -是的
Right. Yeah.
那是  请原谅
It's, uh... Excuse me. Mm-hmm.
鲁迪拜勒
Rudy Baylor.
你好  是我
Hey. Hey there. It's me.
你在干什么
What you doing?
鱼钓得怎么样
How's the fishing going?
嗯  这个  嗯  进行的还不错嗯
Mmm, it's, uh, it's going well.
事实上我现在正在和潜在委托人交谈
I'm actually talking to the prospect right now.
不错  你最好让她签约雇你
Well, you better sign her up.
怎么啦  鲁迪  鲁迪  你听见我说吗
What--Rudy? Rudy? Can you hear me?
很高兴和你见面
I enjoyed meeting you.
鲁迪
Rudy?
是啊  多谢你和我作伴
Yeah, thanks for the company.
嘿  明晚上还继续么
Hey, tomorrow night?
也许行
Maybe.
时间到了  停笔
Time's up. Pencils down.
请把你的考卷往右传
Please pass your test booklets to your right
这样监考员可以把它们收在一起
so that your proctors may gather them up.
我在法学院的第一学年
In my first year at law school,
大家都是相亲相爱的
everybody loved everybody else
因为我们都是学法律的
because we were all studying the law,
而法律是很清高的事
and the law was a noble thing.
到了第三学年
By my third year,
你要庆幸自己没在睡梦里被人谋杀掉
you were lucky if you weren't murdered in your sleep.
人们在考场作弊
People stole exams,
从图书馆里偷取研究资料
hid research materials from the library,
对教授们撒谎
and lied to the professors.
这就是这行的本质
Such is the nature of the profession.
这边
Right here.
半小时之前  她丈夫来过
Half an hour ago, her husband came in...
把一大碗汤泼向她
And threw a bowl of soup at her
因为她不想听到那些
because she just won't get it through her head
-我多爱你之类的甜言蜜语  -这就是我的病房
how much he loves her. This is my room.
十八岁怀孕  结婚  然后就流产了
Pregnant at 18, married, then a miscarriage--
也许就因为他殴打她
probably because he beat her up--
但是  她却仍然不想离开他
and still, she can't leave him.
你得帮我一下
You are gonna have to help me.
我虽没亲眼看到这些
Everything I've ever seen
但一切都告诉我  这姑娘是个失败者
tells me that this girl is a loser,
流产啊断骨啊也许还有更危险的遭遇
scarred and broken and maybe even dangerous,
我以前真没见过像她这样的
but I've never really seen anyone like her before,
与其逃避
and instead of running away,
我要尽我的一切保护她
all I want to do is protect her.
探视时间已过  亲爱的  请长话短说
Visiting hours are over, hon. You kids need to wrap it up.
那么
So...
他该被枪毙
He should be shot.
用铝合金棒球棒打自己妻子的家伙
Any man who'd beat his wife with an aluminum bat
都该被枪毙
needs to be shot.
你怎么会知道的
How did you find out?
有警察的报告  有救护车的报告
There are police reports, there are ambulance reports,
还有医院的病历
there are hospital records.
凯丽  你还想再等多久呢
How long are you gonna wait, Kelly,
等他决定用他的棒球棒打碎你的脑袋吗
until he decides to hit you in the head with that bat of his?
这会致你于死地  你知道吗  你会死的
'Cause that could kill you, you know. That'd be it.
几下你就完蛋了
A couple of good shots to the skull,
看着我  凯丽
Look at me, Kelly.
我能问你点儿事吗
Can I ask you something?
你有父亲或者兄弟吗
Do you have a father or a brother?
为什么问这个
Why?
我向上帝起誓  我会扭断他的脖子
I swear to God I'd break his neck.
没有哥哥吗
No big brother?
没有
No.
没人照顾我  你知道吗
No one to take care of me, you know?
凯丽  我会尽我所能帮你
Kelly, I'll try to help you any way I can,
但你一定得申请离婚
but you have to file for divorce.
趁你还在医院里治疗家暴创伤
Do it now while you're in the hospital
赶快办吧
being treated for the last beating.
现成的证据
It'll sail through.
还有什么更好的证据吗
What better proof is there than that?
我  我不能申请离婚
I...I can't file for a divorce.
为什么不能呢
Why not?
因为他会杀了我
Because he'll kill me.
他一直是对我这么说的
He tells me so all the time.
这决不会发生
That's not gonna happen.
请你递个枕头给我
Could you pass me a pillow, please,
把它垫在我腿下好吗
and put it under my foot?
那边有一只
There's one over there.
这里
Here.
这样行吗
That OK?
嗯  好吧
Yeah! fine
请再把我的睡袍递给我  好吗
Could you pass me my gown, too, please?
好的
Yeah.
多谢
Thanks.
要我帮你穿吗
You need some help putting it on?
不用  你只要背过身去就行
No. Just turn around.
好吧
All right.
噢  你是谁
Ooh! Who are you?
我住在这里  你又是什么人
I live here. Who the hell are you?
噢  我的上帝  我是笛尔伯特的太太
Oh, my gosh. I'm Delbert's wife.
笛尔伯特  谁又是笛尔伯特
Delbert? Who the hell is Delbert?
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
是柏蒂把钥匙交给我的
Birdie gave me the key.
我住在这儿
Do you understand that?
你明白么  你无权待在这里
You have no right to be in here.
行了行了  我明白
Ok Then. I see.
柏蒂要见你
Birdie wants to see you.
协议永久有效
"Agreements are permanent,
且包含上述限制条款
and restrictions mentioned above herein..."
这是什么
What is this?
嗯  你想必就是那个律师了
Well, you must be the lawyer.
我是鲁迪拜勒
I'm Rudy Baylor.
我是笛尔伯特伯德松  柏蒂的小儿子
I'm Delbert Birdsong, Birdie's youngest.
他朝我大喊大叫
He yelled at me.
他让我滚出他的公寓
He told me to get out of his apartment.
你说对了  就是这样
That goes for the both of you.
对你们两位都是
I don't want neither one of you up there
我不希望你们任何一个上去
I do not hope.
我回家来看望我的妈妈
I come home to check on mama,
发觉  她让一个混身发臭的  律师和她一起住
and, damn, she's got a stinkin' lawyer livin' with her.
你是不是在篡改我妈的遗嘱
You been messin' with my mama's will?
她是你妈  为什么不直接问她
Well, she's your mama. Why don't you ask her?
她一句话都不说
She won't say a word.
噢  好嘛
Oh, well,
那我也什么都不能说
then neither can I.
这是律师与委托人之间的隐私
That's a lawyer-client privilege.
但是让我来告诉你
But I tell you what.
我打过好几个电话
I made a couple of phone calls...
嗯
Mm-hmm.
查过某些账目
Verifying some accounts.
你妈妈的第二任丈夫
Your mama's second husband
给她留下了巨额的财产
left her an enormous fortune.
多大呢
How big?
很大
Big.
你不会从中作梗吧  小伙子
I hope you're not meddling, boy.
妈妈  你不是想到我们家去住些日子吗
Mama, wouldn't you just love to come and visit with us
去弗罗里达吧
down in Florida for a while?
妈妈  你会爱上那儿的
You'd love it down there, mama.
妈妈  坐回来吃点儿点心吧  妈妈
Mama, come on back in and get some cake, mama.
我们住的离青年喷水池很近
We...
离那儿只有33英里
We ain't but 33 Miles away and 180 Miles from Disney world.
我们离迪斯尼乐园也只有180英里
We...
丹尼雷  感觉怎么样
How you feeling, Donny Ray?
非常好
Great.
我看上去不是很棒吗
don't I look fantastic?
你觉得能行吗
You feel up to this?
行啊  动身吧
Yeah. Let's go already.
好吧
All right.
按说律师不该和委托人建立私人感情
A lawyer's not supposed to become personally involved with his client,
但是律师和律师还不一样
but there's all kinds of lawyers
委托人也有很多种
and all kinds of clients, too.
都还好吧  宝贝儿
You OK, baby?
雷科  雷科  雷科
Riker! Riker! Riker!
雷科  雷科
Riker! Riker!
还需要点儿什么别的吗
Can I get you guys anything else?
嗯  要点儿嗯
Mmm, want something?
请再给我一杯杰克丹尼尔吧
I'll have a shot of Jack Daniels, please.
干嘛  想宰了我啊
What's it gonna do, kill me?
柏蒂女士  这是我的朋友丹尼雷
Miss Birdie, this is my friend Donny Ray.
噢  丹尼雷
Oh, Donny Ray,
欢迎你的光临
I'm so glad to have you come over and visit.
您好  柏蒂女士
Hello, Miss Birdie.
在--噢
Where--oh.
就这儿
There you go.
你就过来坐在这里吧
You just come right over here and sit down.
放松一下
Just have a rest.
您快把我吃光了
You have me all...
把我围住了
Blocked off here.
嗯
Well...
对不起  柏蒂女士  我得歇会儿
Sorry, Miss Birdie. I got to take a break.
腰酸背痛啊
My back's killing me.
我差点儿忘了  这是寄给你的
I almost forgot. This came for you.
啊  我的上帝
Oh, my God.
呕  太让人激动了不是
Ohh! Isn't it exciting?
我真为你骄傲
Ohh. I'm so proud of you.
嗨  来来  这杯敬鲁迪
Hey, come on. Here's to Rudy.
祝贺你通过考试
Congratulations on passing the bar.
你那是什么
What the hell is that?
冰茶
Iced tea.
祝贺你  鲁迪
Congratulations, Rudy.
孩子们  干得不错啊
That's some good work, boys.
我今天从万蓝德尔的案子拿到一笔钱
I got a check today from the Van Landel settlement.
我要给你们发奖金
I'm giving you boys a bonus.
每人五千五百美金
5,500 each.
谢谢你
Thank you.
再争取多签些合同  啊
Sign up some more cases, huh?
好吧
OK.
嗯
Mmm.
明天一早  准备好了吧
So are we gonna be ready for tomorrow morning?
九点整
9:00?
我们要准备辩论
We're gonna argue
巨大福利保险公司的撤诉请求
Great Benefit's motion to dismiss.
嗯  对  我觉得我们准备好了嗯
Mmm, yeah, I think we're ready. We're ready.
狄克和我很清楚  我想我们准备好了
Deck and I have been going over it. I think we're ready.
但愿如此  因为我可能  嗯
I hope so, because I might, uh...
我可能让你出马辩论  鲁迪
I might have you handle some of that argument, Rudy.
我们要是输了这场官司  会很丢面子的
It would be awfully embarrassing if we lose this case on a dismissal.
老板
Boss?
好吧  我得走了
OK, I got to go.
我来付账
Food's on me.
你们享用吧
Enjoy your meat.
多谢  伯鲁瑟  非常感谢
Thanks a lot, Bruiser. Appreciate it.
情况有些不妙  我确信
Something's about to go down. I'm sure of it.
他以前从不这么分钱
He never split money like that before.
你能想像  他慷慨的背后是什么吗
What do you think's behind his generosity?
得了吧  伙计
Come on, man.
噢  是吗
Oh, yeah?
瞧这里
Here.
昨天  伯鲁瑟过去的一个搭档在大法官面前作证
Yesterday, one of Bruiser's ex-partners testified before a grand jury.
我觉得他和大法官做了笔交易
I think he's cut a deal.
迟早的事
It's just a matter of time
-他会出卖伯鲁瑟  -那又怎样
before he's singing on Bruiser. So what?
到时你就得拍屁股走人
So...You're gonna have to make a move.
走人  狄克  我才刚进来
Make a move? Deck, I just got here.
是吗  嗯  事情也许会很麻烦
Yeah? Well, things might get a little hot.
贿赂陪审员  逃税
Jury-tampering, tax evasion,
敲竹杠  应有尽有
money-skimming, you name it.
我害怕  真的害怕
I'm nervous, real nervous.
你怕什么呢  他们又不能抓你我
What are you nervous about? They can't arrest us.
听着
Listen...
假设他们带着传票和封条来
Supposing they come in with subpoenas and hacksaws. Huh?
他们可以这么干
They can do that.
他们在处理诈骗案时就这么干过
They've been known to do that in racketeering cases.
他们过来  没收所有文件
They come in, they confiscate the files,
拿走所有的计算机  你手里还剩什么
they haul the computers out. What's that leave us?
我并不担心被抓起来
I'm not worried about being arrested.
我担心我的饭碗
I'm worried about my job.
好吧  那你说这些是什么意思
All right, so what are you saying here?
开溜
Let's bolt.
你有多少钱
How much money you got?
我我有五千五百美金
I got...Got $5,500.
我也一样
Me, too.
我们能租一个小办公室
We can rent a small office,
五百美金一月吧
$500 a month.
我们小本经营它六个月
We operate on a shoestring for the first 6 months.
这很不错
It'll be beautiful.
我们平分一切  所有的一切
We split everything, everything
全都五五开
right down the middle, 50-50.
开销  花费  利润  一切都对半开
Costs, expenses, profits--everything right down the middle.
怎么啦
What's the matter?
你不愿意和我合伙吗
You don't want to be my partner?
啊  不是那意思  他们嗯
Mmm, no, it's not--they--
不是那意思  只是你
it's not that. It's just that you...
你提得太突然
You're hitting me with this right now,
我的意思是  你得给我点儿时间  行不行
and I mean, you got to give me a minute, all right?
我是说  你不能说风就是雨啊
I mean, you can't just spring it on me.
我们行动要快
We have to act fast.
好吧  那就动手吧
All right. Let's do it.
我们先干段时间看看
We'll do it for a while, see how it goes.
你手里有几个案子
How many files do you have?
嗯  我  我有三个嗯
Mmm, I... I got 3.
把它们拿出来  带回家
Get them out of there. Take them home,
可别让人抓住  明白
but don't get caught, OK?
有人监视我们吗
Is somebody watching us?
联邦政府
The feds.
我吃得太快了
I'm eatin' too fast.
对不起
Sorry.
嗨  听着  今天早上我去了办公室
Hey. Listen, I went by the office this morning.
联邦调查局把大门给封了
The FBI was chaining up the front door.
伯鲁瑟到了吗
Is Bruiser comin'?
我估计不会来了
I doubt it.
伯鲁瑟和
Arrest warrants have been issued
普林斯已经被通缉了
for both Bruiser and Prince.
放松点儿  你可以
Take esey.
不过是个提案  继续吧
It's just a motion. Go on.
-我  -对  来吧
Me? Yeah. Come on.
我不行啊
I'm gonna be sick.
你熟悉这个案子  你会处理好的
You know this case. You're gonna be fine.
我们用不着执照  走吧
We...
我对勃拉克的案子了如指掌
I've memorized the Black files cold.
我读过所有法学书
I've read all the books on jurisprudence,
了解取证和证物的规则
the rules of evidence and discovery,
但当我环顾法庭
but I take one look around the courtroom,
我才明白自己还乳臭未干
and I realize I haven't even been born yet.
哦  先生  尊敬的法官  哦  呵呵
Excuse me. Uh, sir? Your honor, um, ahem.
我来参加  勃拉克状告巨大福利保险公司的听证
I'm here for the Black vs. Great Benefit hearing.
那么你是谁
And who are you?
哦  鲁迪拜勒嗯
Uh, Rudy Baylor.
我为简李曼斯通律师事务所工作
I work for J. Lyman Stone.
噢  你为简李曼工作
Oh, you work for J. Lyman.
斯涛切是烟草的忠实支持者
Staunch supporter of the tobacco lobby.
斯通先生在哪儿呢
Where's Mr. Stone?
嗯
Mmm...
老实讲  尊敬的法官  我  我不知道
Honestly, your honor, I--I don't know.
他本来该在这里和我汇合
He was supposed to meet me here,
但我不知道他现在在哪里
and I don't know where he is.
嗯  我倒不怎么奇怪
Well, why doesn't that surprise me?
那么你想干什么  你想继续么
So what do you want? You want a continuance.
不是  尊敬的法官
No, your honor.
我  我准备参加提案的辩论
I--I am prepared to argue this motion.
你是个律师吗
Are you a lawyer?
嗯  我刚通过了律师执照考试
Well, I just passed the bar,
而这些人  是我的委托人
and, uh, these are my clients.
斯通先生  只是代理我提交诉讼
Mr. Stone filed this on my behalf
以便等我通过执照考试
until I passed the bar.
哼  你怎么这么大胆
Well, you got a hell of a lot of nerve
没有执照就敢迈进我的法庭
walking into my courtroom without a license.
立即从这里滚出去  拿了执照
Now get the hell out of here, get your license,
然后再回来
and then you come back.
去拿个执照
Get a license!
等你有了该死的执照再回来
Come back when you got a damn license!
如果法庭许可
May it please the court...
我是  莱奥  富楚门
For the record, my name is Leo F. Drummond
来自霆雷博瑞特律师事务所
of Tinley-Brit,
我是巨大福利保险公司的法律顾问
counsel for Great Benefit,
我要说
and I say
要是这个年轻人  已经通过了律师执照考试
if this young man has passed the bar exam,
尊敬的法官  就让他  参加本案的辩论吧
your honor, let him argue the case.
我们欢迎他加入律师的行业
We welcome him to, uh, big-time litigation.
你没有意见吧  楚门先生
You have no objection, Mr. Drummond?
如果法庭许可
If it please the court,
我将很荣幸  介绍拜勒先生
I would be honored to introduce Mr. Baylor
法官  您是可以现在就让他宣誓的
Judge, you can give him the oath right now,
而我也很愿意支持他
and I'll be pleased to stand for him.
你确定你准备好了继续么  拜勒先生
Are you certain you're prepared to proceed, Mr. Baylor?
绝对--
Abso--
是的  尊敬的法官  是这样
Yeah. Your honor, yes.
很好  那么  举起你的右手
Very well, then. Raise your right hand.
你是否庄严地宣誓  鲁迪拜勒
Do you solemnly swear, Rudy Baylor,
你将忠实地  正直地维护美国
that you will support the constitution and the laws
在职业中竭尽全力
conduct yourself in the practice of your profession
尽心尽责么
to the best of your skills and abilities, so help you God?
我发誓
I do.
嗯  很好  那就让我们继续吧
- OK, fine, fine. That's it. - Let's move on.
-恭喜  -谢谢
Congratulations. Thank you.
欢迎投入战斗
Welcome to the war.
一个白痴主持宣誓  还有一个无赖来做担保
Sworn in by a fool and vouched for by a scoundrel.
哈维
Harvey.
我终于是个律师了
I'm a lawyer at last.
请进
Come on in.
请允许我  哈维
May I, Harv?
当然了
Sure.
嗯  请坐
Uh, sit down.
嗯
Mmm...
这场官司让我很烦  拜勒先生
This lawsuit bothers me, Mr. Baylor.
我不想用"无聊"这个词
I wouldn't use the word "Frivolous,"
坦白地说  它没什么价值
but I'm not impressed with the merits of it, to be Frank.
嗯  我利用休闲时间
Ahem. I'm gonna try to sneak some gym time in.
事实上  我真是厌倦了这类官司
In fact, I'm really tired of these type of lawsuits.
我不是在推脱
don't make no excuses.
我倾向于驳回诉讼
I'm inclined to grant the motion to dismiss.
现在  你可以  向联邦法院提起上诉  明白了吧
Now, you can, uh, refile it in federal court, you know,
到别的地方去打这个官司
take it somewhere else.
别来烦我了
I don't want it clogging up my docket.
请原谅  我去一下厕所
Now, excuse me while I go to the can.
你也要去趟
You, too.
鲁迪
Rudy...
我是个价码不菲的律师
I'm a very expensive lawyer
属于一个价码不菲的律师事务所
from a very expensive firm, and, uh...
我手里有很多案子要办
I've had a lot of cases.
玩飞镖也没失过手
I can hit pretty close to the center of the dart board,
我告诉我的委托人  巨大福利保险公司
and I told my clients, Great Benefit,
打这个官司要花很多的钱
that cost alone here gonna be a big deal.
而对于你和你的委托人  也一样
And for you, too. Your side, too.
现在  他们授权我
Now, they've authorized me...
给你和你的委托人
To offer you and your clients...
五万美元来和解这桩案子
$50,000 to settle this thing out.
我甚至还可以让他们再加点
And I--I may even be able to raise that figure up
比如七万五千美元
as high as, uh, maybe 75,000.
然后就不再承担责任  你明白的
No admission of liability, you understand.
当然  嗯
Course, uh...
那么就会引发第三次世界大战
Well then...
轮到我了  可以吧  哈唯
My turn now. May I, Harv?
当然啦
Sure.
嗯
Uh...
我看这儿没多少官司好打  我的孩子
There's not much of a lawsuit here, I'm afraid, son.
可也许我能依靠莱奥
But maybe I could lean on Leo
为和解出个价
to make you an offer of a settlement.
他们也许愿意付些钱给你
They'll probably want to throw some money at you
总比一分钟付莱奥好几千块划算
to keep from paying Leo a thousand bucks a minute.
可他已经代表辩方向我开价了
But he already offered me the cost of the defense.
噢  真的吗  多少
Oh, really? How much?
哦  七万五嗯
Uh, 75,000.
我的天  嗯  仔细想想  我的孩子
Jeez. Well, looky here, son,
你要是不接受的话  一定是疯了
you'd be crazy not to take that.
您这么认为吗
You think so?
七万五  天哪
75,000? Jeez.
这可是一大笔钱
That's a... That's a bunch of money.
这可真不像是莱奥干的
Doesn't sound like Leo.
嗯  我也这么想  他是个大人物
Well, he's a-- he's a great guy.
嗯
Hmm.
怎么样
So?
房间里没有在开会
That was not a meeting in chambers.
那是一场伏击
That was an ambush.
发生了什么事
What happened?
他们插标把我卖了
They tag-teamed me.
是啊
Yeah.
你以为他们敢这么对待伯鲁瑟吗
Think they would have done that to Bruiser?
不会  伯鲁瑟太了解这些了
Nah. Bruiser's too savvy for that.
然后呢
So what?
他们许给我七万五
They offered me 75,000.
好啊  接过来
Good. Take it.
我们应得的三分之一就是两万五  我们正需要钱
Our third is 25,000. We need the money.
海尔法官的态度是驳回上诉
Judge Hale is serious about dismissing this case.
他又老又暴躁
He's an just an old angry man
大概是在那个位置时间久了吧
who's been sitting on that bench too long.
我说  我们所能做的
The best thing we can do is grab what we can
就是减轻他父母的负担
to make things easy on his parents.
保险公司愿意出钱和解
The insurance company made an offer to settle.
什么价钱
What kind of offer?
七万五千美金
$75,000.
他们算过  那是打官司
They figure that's what it's gonna cost
要付的律师费
to pay their lawyers to defend the case.
哦
Oh.
该死的  他们以为这样就能收买我们
Son of a bitches think they can just buy us off.
他们确实这么以为
That's exactly what they think.
你最好和他谈谈
You better talk to him.
你要和解吗  鲁迪
Do you wanna settle, Rudy?
我的意思是  你能拿到其中一部份钱
I mean, some of the money is yours.
决不
No way.
我想让他们曝光
I wanna expose these people.
妈妈  能请给我一杯水吗
Mama, could you get me a glass of water, please?
当然  宝贝
Sure, baby.
不管你能从这个案子拿回什么
Whatever you get out of this case,
用它来照顾我的家
take care of my family with it.
我真的爱他们
I really love them.
我止不住要想
I can't help thinking
我们这些人  你争我夺  每日奔命
that while we're all out there scrambling around for an edge
好像我们永远都不会死
like we're never gonna die,
这个孩子却直视着它
this boy's looking right at it,
独自与命运抗争
and he's doing it almost alone.
我无法想象
I can't even begin
这要有多大的勇气
to imagine the courage it must take.
喂
Hello?
猜猜昨晚谁死了
Guess who died last night.
谁
Who?
你根本没睡过吧
Do you ever sleep?
哈维  海尔
Harvey Hale.
出身名门
It's...
海尔法官
Judge Hale?
是他  心脏病突发
Yep. Croaked with a heart attack.
死在游泳池里
Dropped dead in his swimming pool.
你是在开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
嗯哼嗯
Uh-uh.
你一定是开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
如何处理巨大福利保险公司案
was assigned Great Benefit case in his place.
见鬼  这我怎么会知道
How in the hell am I supposed to know that?
泰荣  开普勒
Tyrone Kipler.
黑人  哈佛毕业  民权捍卫者
Black Harvard civil-rights lawyer.
他不会支持霆雷-博瑞特律师事务所的
He can't stand Tinley-Brit,
他对保险公司毫不留情
and he's tough on insurance companies--
他一直都在控诉他们
sues them all the time.
我们交好运了
Great luck for us.
慢着  慢着
All right, all right.
小子  你知道什么是造雨人吗
You know what a rainmaker is kid?
天上要掉钱了
The bucks are gonna be falling from the sky!
现在是五点  你什么时候到
It's 5:00 right now. What time you coming down?
立马就到
I'll be down in a minute.
赶快来  我们要讨论一下紧急上诉的事
Get down here. We gotta talk about fast-tracking.
马上就到
Coffee's on the way.
好的
OK.
楚门先生
Mr. Drummond...
你对这个案子的紧急上诉有异议
You've objected to the fast-tracking of this case.
理由是什么
What's the problem?
嗯  尊敬的法官  哦
Well, your honor, uh...
这个案子已被海尔大法官  裁决好了
This issue's already been ruled upon by Judge Hale.
我认为紧急上诉所需的准备工作嗯
Uh, the preparations required for fast-tracking the case
对于当事人双方  都是不必要的负担
place an undue burden on both parties, I believe.
毫无意义
Nonsense.
我想问问你  楚门先生
Let me ask you something, Mr. Drummond.
作为一个辩护律师
As a defense lawyer,
你以前是否同意过紧急上诉案件
have you ever agreed to the fast-tracking of a lawsuit?
嗯  尊敬的法官  我想我同意过
Why, your honor, I believe I have.
好吧
Fine.
哪件案子  在哪个法庭审理的
Give me the name of the case and the court it was in.
嗯  呵呵
Well...
我得回去找一下才能告诉你
I got...
好吧  下午三点前给我电话
Well, call me this afternoon by 3:00.
我想三点钟之前我到不了办公室
I don't believe I'm gonna be in before 3:00.
噢  好吧  等你到办公室后  就给我个电话哦
Oh. Well, call me when you get in.
我很想了解你同意紧急上诉的那个案子
I'm very anxious to hear about this case you agreed to fast-track.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
那个孩子正面临死亡  先生们
This boy is about to die, gentlemen.
你们同意我们去为他的证词录音么
You do agree that we need to record his testimony.
好的
Yes, indeed.
当然  尊敬的法官
Of course, your honor.
只不过  我的日程安排得相当紧
It's just my trial calendar is pushing me around pretty good.
下周四下午怎么样
How about next Thursday afternoon?
我没问题  尊敬的法官
Great for me, your honor.
我不行  尊敬的法官
I'm sorry, your honor.
还有整整一个星期
That's a week from today.
我可能要外出
I believe I'm out of town.
对的  星期四我得到外地去
Yes, I am out of town Thursday.
取证时间就定在
Deposition is set for...
下周四下午两点
Next Thursday afternoon at 2 P.M.
假如辩方不大不方便  那对不起了
Sorry if it inconveniences the defense,
但你们应该还有其他人
but God knows there's enough of you guys to handle it.
好了  下一个问题
Now, what's next?
驳回上诉的请求还悬而未决
Take back...
啊  是的
Ah, yes.
那个请求已被否决了
That motion is denied.
嗯
Well...
我想结论就是这样了
I guess that's it.
先生们  我们走吧
Gentlemen, let's go.
尊敬的法官  祝贺您的上任
Congratulations on your appointment, your honor.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
楚门先生
And, Mr. Drummond...
别忘了打电话告诉我
don't forget to call me
你同意了哪个案子的紧急上诉
with the name of that case you agreed to fast-track.
我会找的
I'll look around.
你知道怎么做了吧  我的孩子
You in over your head, son?
绝对是
Absolutely.
狄克想在当地饶舌音乐电台做个广告
Now Deck wants to do an ad on the local rap station.
虽然我一直爱听那个台  但我们负不起广告费
And as much as I'd love to hear it, we can't afford it.
家具  出庭费  传真机花了七百五
Furnishings, bar dues, 750 for a fax machine,
租电脑花了四百块
400 for a lease on a computer,
一辆二手车交完首付
a down payment on a new secondhand car,
我们一文不名了
and we're broke again.
狄克说  他对这种运作很兴奋
Deck says he's thrilled with the way things are going.
凯丽  雷科
Carly...
鲁迪  嗨
Rudy. Hi.
嗨  达特
Hey, Dot.
请进  你好吗
Come in. How are you?
我很好  你好吗
I'm doing good. How you doing?
很好
Good.
听我说  星期三晚上我要到克利夫兰去
Listen, I'm going up to Cleveland Wednesday night.
巨大福利保险公司的总部在那里
It's the headquarters of Great Benefit.
我要收集所有董事的证词
I'm gonna take depositions from all the executives.
哦
Oh.
所以
So...
不用担心开销
And don't worry about expenses, either.
我们会处理的
We're gonna take care of it.
-谢谢你  鲁迪  -没什么
Thank you, Rudy. It's no problem. Shh!
真不好用
It's awkward.
这是我的合伙人  狄克谢佛来尔
My associate, Deck Schifflet.
-你好  -嗨
How do you do? Hi.
嗨  鲁迪
Hey, Rudy...
泰荣来了
Tyrone's here.
好的
OK.
大法官到了
The judge is here.
哦
Oh.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你好
Hi!
请进
Come right in.
这是勃拉克女士
This's
他就是大法官泰荣  开普勒
His honor Tyrone Kipler.
非常荣幸见到您
It's a privilege to meet you.
应该是我感到荣幸
The privilege is mine.
噢  哦  请过来
Oh, uh, come on in.
这地方太小
There's not a lot of room here.
我们到室外去看看
We...
你可以吗  我的孩子
Is that all right with you, son?
当然  可以的
Sure, OK.
我来带路
I'll show you the way.
我看着每小时赚一千美金的
I'm looking at a team of lawyers
律师班子
who are pulling down a $1,000 an hour,
我恨他们
and I hate them.
他们居高临下
From their lofty perch,
对整个司法体系肆意妄为
pissing down on the whole justice system with disdain.
我以前恨他们  是因为我不是对手
I used to hate them because I wasn't good enough for them.
而现在  是因为他们代表的人
Now I hate them for who they represent
和行为
and what they represent.
尊敬的法官  您好吗
Your honor, how are you?
很好  先生
Fine, sir.
但愿这些狗没有吓着你
Hope the dogs didn't startle you.
我们要在室外采集证据
We're doing this thing outside.
室内稍微挤了点
It's a little cramped inside.
找个位子坐下吧
Just have a seat here.
好吧
How you doing?
-你好  -很好
Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好吗  丹尼雷
Hey, Donny Ray?
你已经见过大法官开普勒了
you...
是的
Howdy.
这是  莱奥富楚门
This is Leo F. Drummond
和他的同事们
and associates.
这是谭密  她是法庭书记员
This here is Tammy. She's the court reporter.
嗨
Hi.
让他起誓吧
Swear him in.
你是否发誓  你将给出的证词
Do you swear the testimony you are about to give
都是事实
will be the truth, the whole truth,
只有事实  绝无虚假
and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
是  我起誓
Yes, I do.
我告诉过他了
I told him...
我知道  我知道过来  过来  过来
I know. Come here, come here, come here.
别担心  别担心  这只是个听证
don't worry about it. It's just a deposition.
丹尼雷  我是莱奥楚门
Donny Ray, I'm Leo Drummond.
我代表巨大福利保险公司
I represent Great Benefit,
我非常非常遗憾
and I'm very sorry...
我非常遗憾
I'm very sorry to be here
在这种情形之下来到这里
under these circumstances.
嗯  我们本不该坐在这里
Well, we wouldn't be here
只要你的委托人做了他们份内之事就好
if your clients had done what they should've done.
对不起  我没听清楚
I beg your pardon? I didn't hear that.
-当然了  -给你
Sure.
你胳膊断了吗
Here. Did you break your arm?
对啦
Yep.
你遭遇事故了
You had an accident?
干嘛问哪
Why?
嗯  我是个律师  并且  嗯
Well, I'm a lawyer, and, uh...
把这交给你的母亲  您是他母亲吗
Give this to your mom-- you his mom?
这种意外事故  也许我能帮你们找回些钱来
Maybe I can get you some money for the accident.
帮忙介绍下好吗
Why don't you help with the display?
好的  我先帮一下这位先生
OK. I'll go help this man first.
噢  不不  我来  这样挺好
Oh, no. I got it. It's fine.
我能为您做点儿什么  先生
Can I help you, sir?
噢  我只是看看
Oh, I'm just looking.
旁边有家电影院
There's a cinema down the street.
买张后排  中间的票
Buy a ticket. Center section, back row.
我三十分钟后到
Be there in 30 minutes.
好的
OK.
克利夫想让我生个孩子
Cliff wants me to have a baby.
那  你得做个决定
Well, you have a decision to make.
他跟着了迷似的
He's become obsessed with sex.
他认为这样  就能把我们栓在一起
He thinks it's going to keep us together.
听我说  我真的不想讨论这些
Listen, I really don't want to talk about that.
我只是想见见你
I just wanted to see you.
去克利夫兰的一路上  我好像都能闻到她的香水味
I think I can smell her perfume all the way to Cleveland.
这让我无法集中精力去想  莱奥楚门的那帮人
It's hard keeping my mind on Leo Drummond and his people.
他们会乘头等舱飞过来
They'll be flying in, first class,
酒足饭饱之后
and after a leisurely dinner,
在某个会议室里碰头
they'll meet in some board room
商量怎么来对付我
and discuss my total destruction.
当我在汽车旅馆开房间的时候
Around the time I'm checking into motel 6,
他们却正在高级套房里呼呼大睡
they'll be sleeping soundly in their suites.
养精蓄锐之后
And they'll wake up fresh and rested
准备开战
and ready for war.
这是我要的听证会
It's my deposition,
却在他们的地盘上举行
but it's their turf.
啊  年轻的鲁迪拜勒
Ah, young Rudy Baylor.
真是准时
Just on time, too.
楚门先生
Mr. Drummond.
泰勒  给这个孩子弄杯咖啡
Get this boy some coffee, Tyler.
贾克安德豪尔
Jack Underhall.
鲁迪拜勒
Rudy Baylor.
年轻律师永远是饥渴的
Young lawyer is always a hungry lawyer.
这些都是理赔部和保险受理部的人
All these boys claims, underwriting...
这张桌子边  一定聚集了上百年的法律经验
There must be a 100 years of legal experience gathered around the table.
而我的搭档  却考了六次律师执照考试都失败了
My staff has flunked the bar exam 6 times.
噢  鲁迪  别让
Now, Rudy, don't be intimidated
桌子这边这么多人给吓着
by all these boys on this side of the table.
我保证  要是你在高尔夫球场  碰到他们
I guarantee, you get them on the golf course,
你一定能打败他们
they fold like a cheap suit. Let's see.
让我们看看这是什么
Let's see what we got here.
我想也许该从
I think maybe it's, uh, appropriate
公司设计师贾克安德豪尔
to start with the corporate designee,
这里开始是合适的
Jack Underhall here.
我  我并不这样认为
I--I don't think so.
对不起  你说什么
I beg your pardon?
你听清楚了的
Well, you heard me.
我想从贾奇莱曼奇科开始  她是索赔处理人员
I want to start with, uh, Jackie Lemancyzk, the claims handler.
我觉得最好还是  从安德豪尔先生开始
I think it's best we start with Mr. Underhall.
我应该得到尊重  楚门先生
With all due respect, Mr. Drummond,
这是我要求的听证会
this is my deposition.
我得按我认为合适的顺序  召见这些证人
I'm gonna call these witnesses in the order in which I see fit,
所以最好是从贾奇莱曼奇科开始
so I'd like to start with Jackie Lemancyzk.
也许我们需要打个电话给大法官
Maybe we should just go call the judge.
哦  我不认为这么一大早
Oh, I don't believe we have to get pugilistic
我们就得开始厮杀
this time of the morning.
我没有想要和你厮杀
I'm not admitting to being pugilistic.
我们只是有那么点儿小问题
We're simply having a little problem
关于贾奇莱曼奇科
with, uh, Jackie Lemancyzk.
哦  这位波兰女士身上嗯
Uh, this Polish woman.
什么样的问题呢
What sort of problem?
她已经不在这里工作了
She doesn't work here anymore.
她被开除了吗
Was she fired?
她辞职了
She resigned. She resigned.
嗯  那么  她现在在哪儿嗯
Mmm, well, where is she now? Well...
她不再为我们的委托人工作  所以  嗯
She is no longer working for our client, and, uh,
我们不能再把她作为证人
we can't produce her as a witness,
让我们继续下去
so let's move along.
好吧  鲁塞尔  克劳凯特
All right. Russell Crockett.
在座的谁是  鲁塞尔克劳凯特
Anybody in the room named Russell Crockett?
他也离开了
He's gone, too.
被裁员了
He was downsized.
裁员
Downsized?
嗯  真巧啊
Well, what a coincidence.
我们的委托人进行了  阶段性的裁员
Our client's going through a periodic downsizing.
是啊  这难免的  不是吗
Yeah, that will happen, won't it?
那么艾沃特  鲁富肯
How about Everett, uh, Lufkin...
那个理赔部副总经理呢
Vice President of Claims.
他也被裁员了吗
Has he been downsized, too?
不  他在这儿
No, he's here.
你是  艾沃特  鲁富肯
You're Everett Lufkin?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
我祝贺你
My congratulations...
鲁富肯先生
Mr. Lufkin...
在巨大福利保险公司的大屠杀中
On your miraculous survival
奇迹般地幸存下来
of the carnage of late here at Great Benefit. Whoo.
我也许没有百分百的努力  但我精神抖擞
I may not be 100% today, but I'm here in spirit.
我很好奇
I'm curious.
好奇什么
About what?
我只想知道
I'm just wondering.
你还记得是什么时候第一次出卖自己的吗
Do you even remember when you first sold out?
你小子很狂啊
You're an arrogant little piss ant, aren't you?
我建议你注意礼貌
I advise you to mind your manners.
你可是律师
You're in the big water now.
你在乎我的态度
Mind my manners?
我大老远从孟菲斯来
I come up here from Memphis
来为四个人取证
to depose 4 people,
居然有两个不在
2 of whom are not here,
而你让我注意礼貌
and you tell me to mind my manners?
这个  是你运气不好
Well, it's your dime.
你打算怎么样啊  小子
What's your call, son?
我要从他那里取证
I'm gonna depose him--
坐那里的那位  拉佛金先生
Mr. Lufkin over there--
然后我会收拾行李
then I'm gonna pack up,
回孟菲斯去
I'm gonna go back to Memphis.
没有保险的人就这么死去
So this is how the uninsured die.
有这么多好医生
In a society filled with brilliant doctors
科技如此发达
and state-of-the-art technology,
就这么让这个孩子死去  太可耻了
it's obscene to let this boy just wither away and die.
他有保单在身
He was covered by an insurance policy
她母亲也付了保险金
that his mother paid good money for.
也许钱不是很多  但是足够了
It wasn't big money, but it was good money.
我在这个案子中孤立无援
I'm alone in this trial.
我被人耍  我也很怕
I'm seriously outgunned, and I'm scared,
但是我是正确的
but I'm right.
我坐在这个可怜的孩子旁边  看着他受苦
I sit here with this poor suffering kid,
我发誓  一定要报复
and I swear revenge.
喂
Hello?
鲁迪  是我
Rudy, it's me.
怎么了
What's--what's wrong?
求你帮帮我
I need your help.
你在哪里
Where are you?
店里
I'm at the store.
好  待那里别动  好吗
OK, um, don't move, OK?
我马上就来
I'm gonna be right there.
好的
All right.
我是鲁迪贝勒
Rudy Baylor.
她在这里
She's in here.
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
发生什么事
What happened?
快点  让他看看
Come on, let's show him.
我扶着你呢  别怕
I got you. It's all right. Ohh.
鲁迪  我真高兴你能打电话来
Oh, Rudy, I'm so glad you called.
快进来
Come. Come.
可怜的孩子
Oh, you poor child.
我会照顾你的
I'm gonna take care of you now.
别担心
don't you worry.
别担心  我们能应付
don't you worry. We'll manage just fine.
好的  你知道在哪儿找我
All right. You know where I'll be if you need me.
知道  知道
I do. I do.
把她拯救出来
to get her out of this
不然  那家伙肯定会把她打死
because this guy's never gonna stop until he's killed her.
肯定的
Never.
这
Well...
他本来死不了的
Now it's a wrongful death suit.
混蛋
Gazillions.
迭克
Deck...
多特  我真难过
I'm so sorry, Dot.
真谢谢你能来
Well, thank you so much for coming.
非常感谢
Appreciate it.
会没事的
It'll be OK.
嘿
Hey!
这是布奇  他来找窃听器
This's...
窃听器
For bugs? Shh. Shh.
办公室内有小型窃听器
Here?
谢谢
Thank you.
请慢用
Enjoy your meal.
这个窃听器
This bugging device has got...
有中级电路
Medium-grade circuitry.
可以传送很微弱的信号
It's a weak transmitter.
可能是捷克制的
Probably manufactured in Czechoslovakia.
我认为警察或者联邦调查局不会用这种型号
No, I don't think the cops or the feds would place this.
肯定是其他什么人在窃听
Somebody else is listening.
还有谁想窃听我们
Who else would be listening to us?
嗯
Hmm.
我想到了
I got a pretty good idea.
怎么了
Just checking in.
我只是随便打个电话
I just...
-你要我从城里带什么吗  -不用
You need anything from downtown? No.
嘿  猜猜谁打算庭外和解了
Hey, guess what. Guess who wants to settle.
谁
Who?
多特布莱克
Dot Black.
Dot Black?
我今天过去了一下
I went by there today,
顺便看了看她
and, uh, check up on her.
我给她买了个水果蛋糕
I brought her a fruitcake.
她说已经没有力气
Yeah, and she said she just doesn't have the willpower
打这种耗时的官司了
to stand a long trial
还有
and, uh...
她要多少
How much?
她说17万5就行
She said she'd take 175.
我觉得我们应该同意
I think we should take it.
先这么着吧  明天见
We'll sleep on it. I'll see you tomorrow.
好吧  不过我建议你同意
All right, but I say you take it.
我知道  我听见你的话了  我想想看
I know. I heard you. I'll think about it.
好吧  再见
All right. Bye.
哈哈
Hah.
孩子
Son...
这个家庭已经受够了
This family's been through a hell of a lot,
我觉得那女人会接受庭外和解的
and I feel this woman wants to settle.
我会问问她的
I'll talk to her.
你现在就给她打电话吧
You go ahead and call her.
我就在这等着
I'll wait here one while.
好  我一会打给你  德拉门德先生
I'll get back to you, Mr. Drummond.
再见
Good day.
我对这男孩的死很难过
I'm sorry about the boy.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
听着  我的客户  呃
Listen, my client, uh,
想要和解  鲁迪
wants to settle, Rudy.
我们这么说吧  鲁迪
Let's say, Rudy,
只是讨论一下数目而已
just for the sake of putting the numbers on the board,
假设这个保险被赔付了
that if the claim was covered
我的客户大概要付
that my client should have paid out somewhere
15万到17万5的样子
around 150-175,000.
你这么认为
Well, if you say so.
他们的确窃听了我们的电话
They bugged our phones.
我的确这么认为  所以  呃  我们打算给你们
I do say so. And, uh, we will offer...
我看我们该  告诉开普勒法官这事
Guess we should... Tell Judge Kipler.
不  我反对
I don't think so.
为什么
Why not?
我有个主意
I have an idea.
嗯
Mmm...
有点疯狂的主意
A kind of a crazy idea.
妨碍司法公正
Jury tampering.
我喜欢这样
I love it.
我们最大的恶梦是谁
Who's our biggest nightmare?
法官给了我们陪审团的预选名单
The judge gave us the names
一共92人
of 92 potential jurors.
我们调查了他们的背景
We investigated their backgrounds,
确定了他们对我们有利还是不利
and we rated them with plus or minus numbers.
你打算让我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
-好吧  -什么
All right. Here we go.
任何与他们的直接接触  毫无疑问就是犯罪
What? Any direct contact would of course be a serious offense.
我们在干嘛
What are we doing?
我们要这么做
We're gonna do this thing.
-照我说的做  -好吧
Just do what I say.
喂
Hello.
对  我找鲁迪贝勒
Yeah, uh, Rudy Baylor, please.
我就是嗯
Uh, this is Rudy Baylor.
我是比利波特嗯
Uh, this is Billy Porter.
你今天来我店里了嗯
Uh, you stopped by the shop today.
是的  波特先生
Yes. Mr. Porter.
很感谢你给我回电话
Thank you very much for calling back.
你要干什么
What do you want?!
呃  和一个案子有关嗯
Uh, yes, well, it's about the trial.
你知道的  你是那个案子的陪审团成员
You know, the one you got a jury summons for.
我是那个案子一方的律师
I'm one of the lawyers.
呃  这这合法吗嗯
Uh-huh. Is--is this legal?
呃  当然  当然合法  波特先生嗯
Uh, of course it's legal, Mr. Porter.
不过千万别告诉其他人
Just don't go telling anybody.
我代表那位女士  她孩子死了  是白血病
Look, I represent this lady whose son died of leukemia
而这都是因为  巨大利益保险公司
because the Great Benefit insurance company
不给他们动手术的钱
wouldn't give them the money they needed for an operation.
哦  天啊  这太恐怖了
Oh, why, that sounds awful.
我也有个婶婶得这个病
You know, I had an aunt that had that same disease.
花了很多钱  我叔叔很痛苦
Kept wasting away and my Uncle cried and--
我会尽力的
I'll do what I can.
好的  先生
Well, yes, sir.
谢谢您  波特先生  祝你下午愉快
Now, thank you, Mr. Porter. You have a fine afternoon.
再见
Bye. Bye.
那个  那个婶婶是怎么回事
What--what-- what about the aunt?
那婶婶是哪冒出来的
Where'd the aunt come from?
我怎么知道
I don't know.
你让我装得同情些嘛
You told me to be sympathetic.
我知道  可是你也不用说这么详细吧
I know but you don't have to--
我们回去
Let's go back up there.
我只是想帮忙而已
I'm just trying to help.
快过来
Come on.
我就在你后面
Right behind you.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我下面要问的问题
what I'm about to ask
是今天最重要的问题
is the most important question of the day.
不过也很简单
It's a simple question.
回答是或否就行
Can be answered yes or no.
请听仔细
Listen carefully.
你们是否有人已经就此案被联系过
Have any of y'all been contacted about this case?
这是非常严重的事件
This is serious business.
成功了
Bingo.
我们现在要知道
We need to know now.
让我换种方法提问吧
Let me ask it another way.
你们之中是否有人最近与
Did any of you have a conversation recently
鲁迪贝勒先生
with either Mr. Rudy Baylor
或者他后面那位迭克席夫列特先生谈过话
or directly behind him, Mr. Deck Schifflet.
反对  法官大人
Objection, your honor!
这是侮辱
This is an outrage!
你在做什么  德拉门德先生
What are you doing, Mr. Drummond?
法官大人
Your honor,
我们有证据表明
we have reason to believe
有人试图控制陪审团
that this panel has been tampered with.
他说的是我吧
And he's accusing me.
我不明白你在做什么  德拉门德先生
I don't understand what you're doing, Mr. Drummond.
我也不知道  法官大人
Well, neither do I, your honor.
我也不知道
Neither do I.
请上前
Approach the bench, please.
法官大人  有人试图控制陪审团
Your honor, this panel's been tampered with.
我要证据  立奥
I want proof, Leo.
我不能
I can't say without divulging
泄露秘密情报  法官大人
confidential information, your honor.
你疯了吗
You are just out of your mind.
你看起来不正常
You are acting rather bizarrely.
-我能证明的  -怎么证明
I'm gonna prove it. How?
控告我们这种罪名
Accuse us of something like that.
控制陪审团
Tamper. I--
真可笑
it's ridiculous.
请允许我先问完陪审团
Just allow me to finish questioning the panel.
我相信您会明白事实的
I think the truth will come forth.
你反对吗  贝勒先生
Any objection, Mr. Baylor?
不  我不反对
No, no objection.
那好  继续
Very well. Proceed.
好
Right.
那到底怎么回事
What in the Sam hill is going on up there?
没什么  律师的小伎俩
Oh, it's just lawyer stuff.
波特先生
Mr. Porter.
我想直接问你个问题
I want to ask you a direct question.
可以诚实地回答我
And you...
只要你的问题是诚实的
You ask an honest question,
我就诚实地回答
I'll give you an honest answer.
很好
Fair enough.
波特先生  几天前你有没有
Did you, Mr. Porter, or did you not
和鲁迪贝勒先生
have a phone conversation a few days ago
通过电话吗
with Mr. Rudy Baylor?
废话  当然没有
Hell, no.
我本以为你会给我个诚实的回答
I thought you were gonna give me an honest answer.
我就是实话实说
I gave you an honest answer.
你肯定吗  波特先生
Are you sure, Mr. Porter?
我非常肯定
I'm damn sure.
波特先生
Mr. Porter,
在法庭上
in a courthouse.
在美国法庭上
In a courthouse in the United States,
在田纳西州公正的法庭上
in a courthouse of justice, state of Tennessee,
我说你在说谎
I say you did not provide an honest answer!
你怎么敢说我说谎
don't call me a liar.
德拉门德先生
Mr. Drummond.
你个婊子养的
You son of a bitch.
嘿  把他拉出去
Hey, get off him!
保持法庭秩序
Order in the court!
贝立夫
Bailiff,
把波特先生带出法庭
remove Mr. Porter from this courtroom.
比利波特先生  你被驱逐出陪审团了
Mr. Billy Porter, you are excused from the jury.
法官大人
Your honor,
我要求解散整个陪审团
I move to dismiss the entire panel, your honor.
否决
Denied.
陪审团已经被控制了
It's been tainted.
你
You, uh...
你掉了你的鞋
Your shoe, you left it--
我们可以按现在的陪审团
Are we ready to proceed now
继续吗  德拉门德先生
with the jury selection, Mr. Drummond?
可以  法官大人
I'm ready to proceed, your honor.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们今天就提出诉讼
We'll file it today.
他会疯的
He'll go crazy.
他已经疯了
He already is crazy.
他会干掉你的
He'll come after you.
我正盼着呢
I hope he does.
这火鸡烤的不错
This is that good processed Turkey.
哦
Oh. Oh.
我  我得去法庭了
Well, I gotta get back to court.
我已经迟到了
I'm late. I gotta get back to court.
你的三明治怎么办
What about your sandwich?
我边走边吃吧
Oh, I was gonna take that with me.
好吧
Good, good.
待会见
I'll see you later.
再见
OK?
怎么样了
How'd it go?
克立佛去吃午饭时  我把文件给他了
I served the papers on Cliff when he was on his way to lunch.
他说他要打架
He didn't take it too well,
我说  打群架的人我有的是
but I said I was ready to rumble.
他就软了
He backed down.
不过  老兄  你最好小心点
Hey, man, you better watch your back.
好的
All right.
谢谢你  布奇  非常感谢
Thanks a lot, Butch. I appreciate it.
你庄严宣誓
Do you solemnly swear
你下面要做的证供
that the testimony you're about to give in this cause
全部都是事实
will be the truth, the whole truth,
没有丝毫谎言吗
and nothing but the truth, so help you, God.
是的  我宣誓
Yes, I do.
你可以作证了
You may take the stand.
请告诉法庭你的名字  以便记录
Please state your name for the record.
玛嘉丽布莱克夫人
Mrs. Margarine Black.
好  布莱克夫人
Now, Mrs. Black,
你是丹尼雷布莱克的母亲
you are the mother of Donny Ray Black,
你儿子是否最近因白血病而死去
who recently died of acute myelocytic leukemia
而这些都是因为被告  巨大福利保险公司
because the defendant, Great Benefit--
反对
Objection.
诱导证人
Leading.
反对有效
Sustained.
你的儿子
Your son,
-丹尼雷  需要做手术  -反对
Donny Ray, needed an operation. Objection.
诱导证人
Leading.
反对有效
Sustained.
布莱克夫人  你买这个医疗保险
Mrs. Black, did you purchase this medical policy
是不是想要为你的儿子提供医疗保障
because you were concerned about medical care for your son?
反对
Objection.
对不起  法官大人
I'm sorry, your honor.
诱导证人
Leading.
贝勒先生
Mr. Baylor,
你干嘛不出示一下保单
why don't you show the policy
然后问问她  干嘛要买这个
and ask her why she bought it?
好的
OK.
贝勒先生
Mr. Baylor.
你必须先得到许可  才能上前询问证人
You must ask to approach the witness.
对不起  法官大人
Sorry, your honor.
我请求询问证人
Permission to approach the witness.
批准
You may.
放轻松点
Take it easy.
巨大利益保险公司  1996年7月7日
"Great Benefit. July 7, 1996.
回复  7849909886号保单
"Re: Policy 7849909886.
亲爱的布莱克夫人
"Dear Mrs. Black,
本公司已经7次
"on 7 prior occasions
以书面方式拒绝了你的赔付要求
"this company has denied your claim in writing.
这是第八次拒绝  也是最后一次
"We now deny it for the eighth and final time.
你实在是蠢  蠢  蠢
"You must be stupid, stupid, stupid."
诚挚的  埃佛莱特拉佛金
"Sincerely Everett Lufkin,
理赔部副总经理
Vice President, Claims Department."
请再读一遍
Read it again.
反对
Objection.
无意义的重复  法官大人
Repetitious, your honor.
反对有效
Sustained.
我问完了
I tender the witness.
德拉门德先生
Mr. Drummond.
法官大人
Your honor.
请收起那个投影
Please remove that exhibit.
现在  布莱克夫人
Now, Mrs. Black. Ahem.
把它关掉
Turn it off.
布莱克夫人  你为什么要控告巨大福利保险公司
Mrs. Black, why did you sue
索赔1000万美元呢
Great Benefit for $10 million?
就这么点吗
Is that all?
对不起  您说什么
I beg your pardon.
我认为该索赔更多呢
I thought it was more than that.
是吗
Is that so?
是的  先生  你的委托人有十亿美元
Yes. Your client has about a billion dollars,
而且你的委托人杀了我的儿子
and your client killed my son.
我打算索赔更多
I wanted to sue for a whole lot more.
你拿这笔钱打算怎么办
What would you do with the money?
如果陪审团判给你1000万
If this jury awards you $10 million,
你打算怎么花
what you gonna do with the money?
我会把它们捐给美国白血病研究学会
I'm gonna give it to the American leukemia society.
全部捐掉
Every cent.
我不要你的臭钱
I don't want a dime of your stinking money.
请注意你是宣誓过的  布莱克夫人
Realize you are under oath, Mrs. Black.
请求上前盘问证人  法官大人
Approach the witness, your honor?
批准
You may.
布莱克夫人  我希望你可以读一下保单
Mrs. Black, I want you to read from the policy.
第16页  第K项  第14段  第E款
Page 16, section "K," paragraph 14, item "E,"
保险公司
in which the insurance company
用浅显的英语说
has in plain English wording said
它不负责赔付实验性治疗
that it will not pay for experimental procedures.
你的起诉书中说
Now, your lawsuit says
如果你的儿子接受骨髓移植
that your son would have been saved if he had had
他就能够得救
a bone marrow transplant.
布莱克夫人
Isn't it a fact, Mrs. Black,
美国每年这种骨髓移植
that there are only 7,000
只有七千次
bone marrow transplants performed a year in the United States?
而田纳西州只有不到200次
Less than 200 in the state of Tennessee?
反对  法官大人
Objection, your honor.
他诱导证人
He's leading the witness.
这是在互证  诱导是允许的
This is cross-examination. Leading is allowed.
就诱导而言
Overruled,
反对无效
as to leading.
所以这不是保单赔付范围
So it was not covered by the policy.
还有  布莱克夫人
Now, Mrs. Black,
谁是
who was it, uh...
谁第一个诊断你儿子病情的
Who was it first diagnosed your son's condition?
最开始
Well, at the very beginning,
是贝奇医生
our doctor, Dr. page.
你的家庭医生
That would be your family physician?
是的  先生
Yes, sir, it would.
他是个好医生吗
Is he a good doctor?
他是个很好的医生
He's a very good doctor.
那么  布莱克夫人
And is it not true, Mrs. Black,
这个诚恳而能力卓著的医生
that this capable, truthful man
是不是反复告诉过你
told you repeatedly that a bone marrow transplant
因为你儿子所患的白血病类型特殊
would do your son no good
骨髓移植对你儿子的病情不利
because of the type of leukemia he had?
不  没有
Well, no.
他没有说过
No, he did not.
他没这么说过
He didn't say that.
他不是那么对我说的
Not like that, to me.
请求上前询问证人  法官大人
Approach the witness, your honor?
批准
You may.
布莱克夫人  这是不是贝奇医生的信签
Mrs. Black, is this not Dr. page's letterhead?
他是不是在底下签字了
And at the bottom there, is that not his signature?
他不能这么做
He can't do that.
为什么
Why?
因为他不能这么
Because he can't introduce evidence
提出证据  更何况那只是道听途说
that way. Plus it's hearsay.
反对  法官大人
Objection, your honor.
布莱克家庭医生给德拉门德先生的
A--a letter from--from the Blacks' family physician
信是不可接受的
to Mr. Drummond is inadmissible.
很正确  法官大人
That is quite correct, your honor.
我没有要求此信
And I'm not asking for this letter
被作为呈堂证供
to be admitted into evidence.
我只是想知道  证人是否
I'm simply asking that this witness
可以读一下这封信
be allowed to read the letter
这是根据田纳西州
under rule 612 of the Tennessee
取证法第612条
rules of evidence.
是为了让她恢复回忆
So her recollection can be refreshed.
贝勒先生  你觉得呢
Mr. Baylor, what do you say?
我不知道  法官大人
I don't know, your honor.
但我反对这样
I just object to this.
而且在预审举证时
And also we were not furnished this letter
这封信并未被提出
in pre-trial discovery.
对此你有何解释  德拉门德先生
What do you say to that, Mr. Drummond?
我当时不知道会用到这封信
I had no idea this letter would be needed.
我本来以为这位女士  会真实的告诉我们
I expected this lady to tell the truth
她的医生对她说了什么
about what her doctor told her.
还有什么事吗  贝勒先生
Anything else, Mr. Baylor?
没了
No.
德拉门德先生
Mr. Drummond,
我不反对
I'm gonna give you a little latitude,
但是最好别扯太远了
but don't stray too far.
没问题  法官大人  现在  布莱克夫人
Very well, your honor. Now, Mrs. Black,
这封信有没有让你回忆起
does that letter refresh your recollection
丹尼雷的那种白血病类型
as to whether or not Donny Ray's leukemia
到底能不能通过
was the kind that could be helped
骨髓移植治疗呢
with a bone marrow transplant?
可是  他不是专家
Well, see, now, he is not a specialist.
但他是持照医师
But he is a licensed,
很有经验  年富力强
experienced, capable physician
而且反覆告诉过你
who lovingly told you time and time again
你理智上无法接受的事情
what you quite understandably did not want to accept:
不管怎么治疗
That your son was going to die of leukemia
你的儿子仍然会因为白血病而死
despite the best efforts of medical science.
是不是
Is that not true?
但是他不是这方面的专家
But he wasn't a specialist.
我不相信他
I didn't believe him.
不仅是信不信他的问题  夫人
Not only did you not believe him, ma'am,
更重要的是你失去了我
but you were less than truthful with me
及陪审团的信任
and with this jury moments ago
你可是发过誓的
when you told us under oath
刚才你说贝奇医生没有说过
that Dr. page never said that your son
你儿子的白血病类型
had the type of leukemia that could not be treated
无法通过骨髓移植治疗
by a bone marrow transplant.
我相信你的原话是
I believe your exact words were,
他没这么说过
"he never said that.
他不是那么
"Not like that
对我说的
to me."
他不是专家
He wasn't a specialist.
我只是希望丹尼雷
I just wanted Donny Ray
可以接受最好的治疗
to have the best medical treatment available.
换了你  也会这么做的
You'd do the same thing.
当然  夫人
Of course, ma'am.
当然
Of course.
我问完了
That'll be all.
你可以退席了  布莱克夫人
You may step down, Mrs. Black.
我是不是做的不好
I didn't do very good, did I?
不  不  你做的很好  很好
Oh, no, no, you did fine. You did fine.
没关系  陪审团会
It's all right. The jury can see
明确知道他想干什么的
exactly what he's up to.
陪审团会知道的
The jury can see what he's up to.
我想抽烟
I need a smoke.
我知道你需要
I know you do.
我们过会再抽
We're gonna get to that later.
我希望他没有换过锁
I hope he hasn't changed the locks.
你害怕吗
Are you scared?
是的
Yeah.
我们干吧
Let's do it.
真成猪窝了
What a pig.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
快点  凯莉  快点
Hurry, Kelly. Come on.
我的东西基本都在衣橱里
There's more of my stuff in the closet.
这儿的东西你是拿不光的  凯莉
You can't take everything, Kelly.
哦  不
Oh, no.
嘿  你好啊
Hey, hello!
我回家啦
I'm home!
哇  真没想到
Well, what do you know?
看看什么人来了
What do we have here?
你们俩在这里干嘛  啊
What you two been doing in here, huh?
嘿  别激动  好吗
Hey, take it easy, all right?
过来  告诉我
Come on, tell me.
老兄  放轻松点
Mam. take esey.
闭嘴
You shut up!
嘿  听着  别激动
Hey, listen, Buddy, all right.
我才不听你废话呢
I ain't listening to nothing!
别激动
Take it easy.
你让我很难受
You hurt me so bad.
你干嘛要这么对我
Why are you doing this to me?!
不  克立佛
No, Cliff!
快跑
Run!
鲁迪  鲁迪
Rudy, Rudy!
克立佛
Cliff!
你这个笨蛋  你在干嘛
You idiot, what are you doing?!
你看到了吧
You see what you did?
凯莉
Kelly!
这就是你想要的
Is this what you wanted?
不是我的错哦
It's not my fault!
我是爱你的  我爱你
I love you! I love you!
鲁迪
Rudy!
别打了  鲁迪
Stop it, Rudy.
别打
Stop. Ohh.
给我那根棒子  快走
Give me the bat and leave.
什么
What?
给我那根棒子  快走
Give me the bat and leave.
你今天晚上没有来过
You were not here tonight.
给我那根棒子
Give me the bat.
快走  鲁迪
Go, Rudy.
你今天晚上没有来过
You were not here tonight.
他最终杀了她
He's finally killed her.
不  是男的死了  她把他杀了
No, it's him. He's dead.
你肯定
You sure?
我刚刚看过她的
Just saw her.
怎么发生的
How'd it happen?
我不知道
I don't know.
有人说  当你谋杀一个人时
They say when you commit a murder,
你起码犯了25项错误
you make at least 25 mistakes,
过后  你要是能记住其中5项就不错了
and later you're lucky if you remember 5 of 'em.
这是自卫行为
It was self-defense,
但是我没法忘记他死了
but I can't get past the fact that he's dead.
这个错误充斥了我的大脑
And the mistakes are piling up in my mind so fast
我没法思考了
I can't think.
但是凯莉知道
But Kelly knew.
她知道该做什么
She knew what to do.
她知道这是好机会
She knew it was time.
当那些事情
With everything that was happening
一起发生的时候
and all that was at stake,
她只想到我的安全
her first thought was for my safety.
而我把她一个人扔在那里
And I left her in there all alone.
该死的
Damn it!
该死  凯莉
God damn you, Kelly!
这到底发生什么了
What the hell's going on here?
你到底做什么了
What the hell did you do?
你杀了我的儿子
You killed my son!
你去死
God damn you!
对不起  我是她的律师
Excuse me. I'm her lawyer.
我要求她被问讯时  我能在场
I insist on being here while she's being questioned.
这是你的律师
This is your attorney?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我希望能够保释她  由我来监管
I want her released to my custody.
我不能这样做
I can't do that
我不知道你是哪种律师
I don't know what kind of lawyer you are,
不过这是人命官司
but we got a dead body here,
只有法官才能作出是否保释的决定
and bond needs to be set by a judge.
我会进监狱吗
I'm going to jail?
你们能给她安排个单间吗
Well, can we arrange for a private cell?
我说  小子  我又不是监狱长
Look, asshole, I don't run the jail.
你知道该怎么做的
You got a better way of doing things,
去和监狱长谈谈
then you need to talk to the jailer.
他们可喜欢律师了  是不
They love lawyers down there, right?
我说
Look...
要是你的律师管用的话
If your lawyer here is worth his salt,
明天你就能离开这里
you'll be out of here
只要你交了保释金
sometime tomorrow if you can post bond, OK?
好吧
OK.
-你们只有5分钟  -谢谢你
You got 5. Thank you.
他们从窗口那里看着我们
They're watching us through that window there,
而且这个房间可能安了窃听器
and this room is probably bugged,
所以你说话要小心
so just be careful what you say.
一般杀人罪  是什么意思
What does "manslaughter" mean?
就是说非故意杀人
It's just murder without the element of intent.
我还能活多久
How much time could I get?
不  不  你得先被定罪才可能判刑
No, no, no, you have to be convicted first.
而我不会让你定罪的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
不可能定罪
That's not gonna happen.
夫人  请把双手交叉在身后放好
Cross your wrists behind you please, ma'am.
这边走  夫人
This way, ma'am.
拉佛金先生
Mr. Lufkin,
你是巨大福利保险公司理赔部的副总经理  是不是
you are the Vice President of Claims at Great Benefit, are you not?
是的
Yes, I am.
我请求询问证人  法官大人
Approach the witness, your honor?
批准
You may.
你认得这个吗
You recognize this?
继续
Go on.
读过陪审团听
Read that to the jury.
亲爱的布莱克夫人
"Dear Mrs. Black,
本公司已经7次
"on 7 prior occasions
以书面方式拒绝了你的赔付要求
"this company has denied your claim in writing.
这是第八次拒绝  也是最后一次
"We now deny it for the eighth and final time.
你实在是蠢  蠢  蠢
"You must be stupid, stupid, stupid.
诚挚的  埃佛莱特拉佛金
"Sincerely Everett Lufkin,
索赔部  副总经理
Vice President, Claims."
这是你写的
That's you?
是的
Yes.
你打算作何解释
How do you explain that?
当时我个人遇到了很多困难
It was a difficult time for me personally.
我有很多压力
I was under a lot of stress.
我们已经7次拒赔了
We had denied this claim 7 times before.
我只是想强调一下
I was trying to be emphatic.
我有点用词不当
I snapped.
我很后悔写了这封信
I regret having written the letter,
我愿意道歉
and I apologize.
你不觉得现在道歉太晚了点吗
don't you think it's a little late for an apology?
也许
Maybe.
Maybe?
那个孩子已经死了  是不是
The boy is dead, isn't he?
是的
Yes.
那么  拉佛金先生
Now, Mr. Lufkin,
杰琪莱曼切克  是谁
who is Jackie Lemancyzk?
杰琪莱曼切克  曾经是理赔审核员
Jackie Lemancyzk is a former claims handler.
她在你的部门工作
And did she work in your department?
是的
Yes.
她什么时候离开公司的
And when did she stop working for Great Benefit?
确切日期我记不得了
I don't remember the day.
是不是10月30日
How about October 30?
好像差不多
Sounds close.
那就是在她将要为此案
Wasn't that just 2 days before she was scheduled
出庭作证的两天前
to give a deposition in this case?
我真的记不得了
I really don't remember.
我希望能让证人恢复一下记忆
I'd like to refresh the witness' recollection
也即根据第612条法令
under rule 612.
是10月30日
October 30th.
很明显是的
Apparently.
而这正是她将为此案出庭的
And that was just 2 days before she was scheduled
两天前
to give a deposition in this matter?
我想是吧
I guess so.
而正是她
And she was the person responsible
处理丹尼雷的理赔申请
for handling Donny Ray Black's claim,
是不是
was she not?
是的
That's correct.
你把她辞了
And you fired her?
当然不是我
Of course not.
那么  你怎么把她赶走的
Well, how'd you get rid of her?
她是自己提出辞职的
She resigned.
就在你给我的信中就能看到
It's right here in the letter you just gave me.
哦  那么她干嘛要辞职哦
Oh. Why'd she resign?
我在此  因个人原因辞职
"I hereby resign for personal reasons"
所以是她自愿
so it was her idea
放弃工作的
to leave her job?
她就是那么写的
That's what it says.
我问完了
Nothing further.
你可以退席了  先生
You may step down, sir.
你好
Hello.
嗨  我是杰琪莱曼切克的兄弟  我叫詹姆斯
Hi. I'm Jackie Lemancyzk's brother James.
我能看看她吗
Is it possible to see her?
-詹姆斯莱曼切克  -是的
James Lemancyzk? Yes.
稍等
One minute.
全体起立
All rise.
请让我解释一下  莱曼切克小姐
Let me explain, Miss Lemancyzk.
其实我不是你的兄弟
I'm really not your brother.
鲁迪
Rudy. Good.
来见见  杰琪莱曼切克
I'd like you to meet Jackie Lemancyzk.
这是  杰琪莱曼切克
This is Jackie Lemancyzk.
这是卡尔  他一定要跟着她
Where she goes, Carl goes.
这是我的合伙人
This is my partner,
鲁迪.S.贝勒
Rudy S. Baylor.
请把你告诉过我的  再和他说一遍
Just tell him what you told me.
莱曼切克小姐
Miss Lemancyzk.
很高兴见到你
It's a pleasure to meet you.
我可以坐下吗
Is it all right if I sit down?
当然
Sure, sure.
很好  莱曼切克小姐
All right, Miss Lemancyzk,
我想和你谈谈  布莱克的理赔申请
let's talk about the Black file.
那是由你处理的
It was assigned to you?
是的
Yes, that's correct.
布莱克夫人的申请  最开始是由我处理的
The initial claim from Mrs. Black
我给她发了一封拒赔信
I sent her a letter of denial.
为什么
Why?
因为所有的索赔请求  一开始都是拒绝的
Because all claims were initially denied.
所有的索赔请求
All claims?
所有的
All claims.
听着  他们是这么干的
OK, this is how it works.
保单
The policy...
是挨家挨户在穷人区兜售的
Is sold door to door in the poorer neighborhoods.
每周用现金结款
Paid in cash each week.
如果有理赔申请  就交给某个业务员处理
The claim comes in and is assigned to a handler.
所谓的处理  其实就是低级的打字
That's basically a low level paper pusher.
不管是什么申请  业务员看过申请后
Anyway, the handler reviews it
就马上给投保人回信
and immediately sends a letter to the insured
拒绝赔付
denying the claim.
然后理赔部会把档案发给保险部
The claims handler then sends the file over to underwriting.
保险部会给理赔部复函
Underwriting sends a memo back to claims
注明  未经保险部同意  不得赔付
saying, "don't pay this until you hear from us."
对了  你要记住
Now, what you should keep in mind
虽然这些人都是为这个大公司干活
is that even though all these people work for this big company,
即使他们都在同一大楼里工作
and they all work in the same building,
他们却互不相识
they don't know each other.
也不知道彼此的部门打算怎么办
Nor do they know what the other department is up to.
这些都是有意如此的
Now, this is very intentional.
部门之间互相敌视  互不关心
The departments are kept at war with each other.
同时
Now, meanwhile,
保险的客户们
there's the client.
不停的接到这种拒付信
And they're getting all these letters.
有些来自理赔部  有些来自保险部
Some from claims, some from underwriting,
大多数人就此放弃了
and most people give up.
而这些  当然
And this, of course, is...
也是经过精心设计的
Intended.
你的下一个证人  贝勒先生
Your next witness, Mr. Baylor.
原告方传召  杰琪莱曼切克
Plaintiff calls Jackie Lemancyzk.
他说什么
What'd he say? Ohh.
反对  法官大人
Objection, your honor.
我可以过来和您说话吗
Approach the bench?
可以
You may.
这是突然袭击  法官大人
This is a complete surprise, your honor.
为什么  她是可传召的证人之一啊
Why? She's listed as a potential witness.
但我们应该提前得到通知的
We have a right to be forewarned.
我从来不知道她失踪了啊
I never...
你得回答这个问题  贝勒先生
It's a fair question, Mr. Baylor.
这是我第一个案子
Well, it's my first trial.
那也不行
That's not good enough.
这事关公平  法官大人
It is a matter of fairness, your honor.
我们应该事前知道你要传召的证人
We have a right to be notified about your witness.
我同意
I agree.
你是说  她不能出庭作证
Are you telling me she can't testify?
在预审名单中有她的名字  法官大人
She's listed in the pretrial order, your honor.
根据第26条法律第6款
Pursuant to rule 26.06,
我们有权传召她为证人
we have the right to call her as a witness.
反对无效
Objection overruled.
去背一遍吧
Go memorize.
请告诉法庭你的姓名  以便记录
State your name for the record.
杰琪  莱曼切克
Jackie Lemancyzk.
莱曼切克小姐
Miss Lemancyzk,
你为巨大福利保险公司工作了多久
how long did you work for Great Benefit?
6年
6 years.
什么时候结束的
And when did your employment end?
10月30日
October 30th.
你为什么不干了
How did it end?
我被解雇了
I was fired.
你是说你不是辞职的
You mean you did not resign?
不  我是被辞退的
No, I was fired.
我可以上前询问证人吗  法官大人
Approach the witness, your honor?
要求批准
You may.
我有些疑惑啊  莱曼切克小姐
I am baffled, Miss Lemancyzk,
我这里有封信
because I have this letter here,
上面说  你因为私人原因辞职的
and it says you quit for personal reasons.
这是在撒谎
The letter is a lie.
我是被辞退的
I was fired so the company could claim
这样公司就可以说我不在那里干了
that I no longer worked there.
你可以向法庭指出
Can you please point out the man in the courtroom
是谁让你写了这封信的吗
who made you write this letter?
杰克安德霍尔
Jack Underhall.
他告诉我我必须马上离开
He told me I was leaving immediately,
当时我有两个选择
and I had 2 choices--
我可以说这是开除  而我就一无所获
I could call it a firing and leave with nothing,
不然我就可以写那封信
or I could write that letter,
说这是辞职
call it a resignation,
而公司会给我1万美元现金
and the company would give me $10,000 in cash
让我保持沉默
to keep quiet.
而且我当时  必须马上在他面前做出选择
And I had to make that decision right there in his presence.
请继续
Go on.
我拿了钱
I took the cash...
而且我还签了一份保证书
And I also signed a letter saying I would never discuss
保证不和任何人谈论我经手的理赔申请
any of my claims files with anybody.
包括布莱克家的理赔申请么
Including the Black file?
特别是布莱克的申请
Specifically the Black file.
那你知道那个申请应该得到赔付
So you knew that claim should have been paid?
谁都知道
Everybody knew...
但公司玩的是赌赔率
But the company was playing the odds.
赌什么
What odds?
赌投保人不会去请律师
The odds that the insured would not consult a lawyer.
就是说  在那段时间内
Now, during that time...
你是高级理赔审核员么
You were a senior claims examiner?
是的
Yes, that's correct.
那么在那段期间  你有没有
During that time, was there ever an occasion
得到任何指示
when you were given instructions
告诉你该如何处理这些申请
regarding how you should handle claims?
一年之内拒绝一切赔付
Deny all claims for a year.
把省下来的钱加起来
Add up the money saved,
扣除庭外和解所需的开销
deduct the amount spent on quick court settlements,
还会剩下一大笔
and there's a pot of gold left.
批准
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
请给我第6号证物
Number 6, please.
这是被标记为
Here's what has heretofore been marked
第6号证物的文件
defense exhibit number 6.
你认得它吗
Do you recognize this?
是的  这是巨大福利保险公司的理赔手册
Yes. It's a Great Benefits company claims manual.
请你帮我个忙
Would you do me a favor
翻到第U项吗
and just flip over to section "U," please?
这里没有第U项
There is no section "U."
但是你在做高级理赔审核员的时候
But do you remember a section "U"
你记得那里有第U项
when you were a senior claims examiner?
是的  我记得
Yes, I do.
第U项是附加条款
Section "U" was an executive memorandum
位于高级审核员的工作手册中
in the senior examiners manual.
谢谢你
Thank you.
法官大人
Your honor,
这是杰琪莱曼切克真正的高级理赔手册
this is Jackie Lemancyzk's actual senior claims manual,
这里面有一项附加条款
and within it, there is an executive memorandum
被列为第U项
entitled section "U."
我请求上前询问
I ask that I might approach--
反对  法官大人  我们可以过来说话吗
objection, your honor. Approach the bench?
法官大人  我们得到的文件不全
Your honor, we were not given a complete manual.
法官大人  这份文件中的
Your honor, this document contains
附加条款部分是非法窃取的
executive memoranda that are stolen work papers
不能作为证据
and may not be admitted.
May not be admitted?
立奥  你能够证明吗
Can you prove this, Leo?
法官大人  我请求你禁止他宣读该材料
Your honor, I ask that you instruct my colleague here not to read from
并且不要使用任何存在嫌疑的证据
nor to make reference to any suspect--
我不理解这为什么不能作为证据
I don't understand why this is not admissible.
它不是在正确的时间内获得的
It was not proffered at the correct time,
我们不知道他怎么得到它的
nor do we know how it was obtained--
我昨天晚上才知道  存在这个东西
I just found out about this last night.
假设我现在不接受这项证物
Assuming that I can't get this in now,
你还有其他问题要问证人吗
do you have any more questions for the witness?
没了  法官大人
No, your honor.
你现在可以询问了  德拉门德先生
You may cross-examine, Mr. Drummond.
谢谢你
Thank you.
莱曼切克小姐
Is it true, Miss Lemancyzk...
请问你最近是否
That you have recently been committed
入院治疗很多疾病
to an institution for various problems?
我没有入院
I was not committed.
我只是喝了很多酒  精神压抑
I am suffering from alcoholism and depression,
我是自愿去医院检查的
and I voluntarily checked into a facility.
我本应享受巨大福利保险公司的集体保险
I was supposed to be covered by my group policy at Great Benefit,
当然  现在他们拒赔了
and they, of course, are denying my claim.
这大概就是你来这里的原因吧  莱曼切克小姐
Is that why you're here, Miss Lemancyzk?
因为你很气愤巨大福利保险公司
Because you're angry with Great Benefit?
莱曼切克小姐
Miss Lemancyzk?
我恨这个保险公司
I hate Great Benefit
我也恨大多数在那工作的蛀虫
and most of the worms that work there.
那你和拉佛金先生上床的时候
Did you feel Mr. Lufkin was a worm
你是不是觉得他也是蛀虫之一
when you were sleeping with him?
反对
Objection.
法官大人
Your honor,
德拉门德先生可能对这个很感兴趣
Mr. Drummond might find this fun to talk about,
但这个与本案无关
but this is not relevant at all.
哦  我可不感兴趣
Oh, there's no fun for me.
让我们看看究竟是怎么回事
Let me...
你是否承认和拉佛金先生有特殊关系
You admit to having an affair with Mr. Lufkin?
莱曼切克小姐
Miss Lemancyzk?
只要我和公司的高层保持性关系
As long as I had sex with certain executives at Great Benefit,
我的工资就会增加  就会得到提拔
my pay was increased, and I was promoted.
否则  我就会被降职
When I stopped, I was demoted.
莱曼切克小姐
Miss Lemancyzk,
作为巨大福利保险公司的雇员
as an employee of Great Benefit,
你承诺过不会泄露
you promised not to disclose
属于机密的理赔信息
confidential private claims information.
-是不是  -是的
Yes? Yes.
事实上  你说过要保守秘密
In fact, you testified that you sealed that promise
并索要1万美元作为报酬  是不是
by demand of payment for $10,000, didn't you?
那笔钱不是我要求的
That payment was not my idea.
但是你接受了  是不是
But you accepted it, didn't you?
你收了钱
You put it right in your pocketbook.
可你心里
Even though in your mind,
却丝毫没有要保守这些秘密的意思
you never intended to keep that promise.
事实上  你对巨大福利保险公司
In fact, you were very angry
和拉佛金先生切齿痛恨  是不是
at Great Benefit and Mr. Lufkin, weren't you?
你知道  他们在欺负我
You know, they preyed on me,
因为我穷  单身一人带着2个孩子
because I was broke, and I was single, and I had 2 kids.
而你告诉他  你打算去见他的妻子
So you told him you're gonna go to his wife,
而那一万美元就是勒索  对不对
that was just a piece of blackmail, wasn't it?
只是你向你痛恨的公司  敲诈的钱财
A way to extort money from the company you hated!
是不是
Isn't that right?
不  不对
No, that's not true.
事实上  你今天的作证完全是一场谎言
In fact, your testimony here today is just a lie.
你偷窃了公司的文件
You stole company work papers,
还有机密材料  藉以进行敲诈
confidential reports as blackmail for revenge.
恶魔也不过如此吧  莱曼切克小姐
Hell hath no fury as what, Miss Lemancyzk?
真是个卑鄙的女人
A woman scorned!
我法官大人  我要求将所有这些
Your honor, I move that all documents
莱曼切克小姐提供给控方的文件
provided the plaintiff by Miss Jackie Lemancyzk
都作为窃取的文件
be deemed stolen work papers
禁止列为证物
and struck from these proceedings.
根据法庭所看到的事实
Based on the evidence presently before the court,
这些文件不予接受
these documents are inadmissible. Ohh.
我没有问题了
No further questions.
谢谢你  德拉门德先生
Thank you, Mr. Drummond.
贝勒先生
Mr. Baylor.
莱曼切克小姐  你可以下来了
You may step down, Miss Lemancyzk.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你好
Hello.
-你好  -这是迭克席夫列特
Hi. This is Deck Schifflet.
我要找大个儿雷诺  你能帮我接一下吗
I need to speak to big rhino. Can you connect me?
大个儿雷诺  稍等
Big rhino? Just a second.
好
OK.
你好
Hello?
嘿  老板  我是迭克
Hey, boss, it's deck.
嗨  迭克  你怎么样啊
Oh, hey, deck, how you doing?
很好  你呢
Good. How are you?
哦  我也很好
Well, I'm cool.
你还在吗
Are you here?
我无处不在
Well, I'm here and there.
啊  对
Ah, yeah, here and there.
听着  我有个案子  证据是窃取的
Listen, I got a stolen-evidence situation.
窃取的证据
OK. Stolen evidence, uh...
让我想想看  呃
Let me see, uh...
你查一下德索托的案子
OK. The De Soto case.
德索托
De Soto?
卡尔曼德索托  记得他吗
Carmine De Soto. You remember him?
红宝石俱乐部
Club Ruby.
是的嗯
Uh-huh.
我在哪能找到这案子
Where--where do I find that?
呃  大概在92年那卷嗯
Uh, around '92, you'll find it, uh,
我想想看  好像是650
let's see, 650 something, uh...
西南第二上诉庭
Southwest second.
老板  你真救了我的命了
Boss, you're a lifesaver.
92年
'92?
是的  红宝石俱乐部的案子
Yeah. Club Ruby case.
92年
'92...
卡尔曼德索托
Carmine De Soto.
红宝石俱乐部
Club Ruby.
那是上诉法庭的案子
It's from the appellate court.
对  对  我想起来了
Yeah. It kind of rings a bell.
我找到了
I got it!
从布鲁泽那里弄来的
And from Bruiser, of all people.
布鲁泽  我还以为你不知道布鲁泽在哪里呢
Bruiser? I thought you didn't know where Bruiser was.
我  我是不知道  但是我有个紧急联络号码
Well, I don't, but I got an emergency-contact number.
我给他们打了个电话  他们给我接通了
I call them, they get me in touch with him.
鲁迪
Look, Rudy,
布鲁泽最清楚窃取证据的事情了
nobody knows more than Bruiser about stolen evidence.
这算他的看家本领了
You might say it's his stock and trade.
你好
Hello?
-喂  -鲁迪贝勒先生
Mr. Rudy Baylor?
你今晚能来下我们法庭吗
Can you come to the courthouse tonight?
我想和你谈谈凯莉莱克的案子
I'd like to discuss the Kelly Riker case.
-当然  -到6号房间来
Sure. Come to room 6.
我们有办法对付这群混蛋啦
There's an advantage to dealing with pimps and thieves.
在卡尔曼德索托  起诉红宝石俱乐部的案子里
In the case of Carmine De Soto vs. The Club Ruby,
有好多的窃取而来的证据
there are reams of stolen evidence.
布鲁泽自己搞的这个案子
Now, Bruiser worked on this stuff himself.
现在不行  我得走了
Not now. I got to go.
你要走
You got to go?
巨大福利公司的首席执行官明天就要来了
You got the CEO of Great Benefit coming in tomorrow.
我说  我们得给他好看的
We--we got to nail this guy, come on.
祝你好运  凯莉
Good luck, Kelly.
谢谢
Thanks.
我和地区检察官谈过了
I met with the D.A.
她不打算起诉
She's not gonna prosecute.
她认为你没有罪
Said she'd never get a conviction.
这只是自卫  凯莉
It was self-defense, Kelly.
控方打算传召维尔佛莱德奇利上庭作证
The plaintiff would like to call Wilfred Keeley to the stand.
请举起你的右手
Raise your right hand, please.
你愿意庄严宣誓
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony
你在此所作证供
you're about to give in this cause
全是事实
will be the truth, the whole truth,
并无丝毫虚言吗
and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
是的
I do.
你可以作证了
You may take the stand.
请告诉法庭你的名字  以便记录
State your name for the record.
维尔佛莱德奇利
Wilfred Keeley.
我可以上前询问证人吗
May I approach the witness, your honor?
批准
You may.
奇利先生  呃  在这个巨大福利公司的册子里面
Mr. Keeley, uh, in this Great Benefit brochure,
这个是不是你  这是你的名字吗
is that you? Is that your name?
是的
Yes.
那这些缩写指什么
And what do those initials stand for?
你是说CEO
CEO?
是的  它们指什么  CEO  指什么
Yeah. What do they stand for? What does "CEO" mean?
首席执行官
Chief executive officer.
首席执行官  谢谢你  谢谢你
Chief executive officer. Thank you, thank you.
就是说  你是你是头儿了
So you're the-- you're the guy.
你是主要人物  你说了算
You're the main guy, you're the cheese.
权力由你掌控
The buck stops with you.
是的  你可以这么说
You could say that, yes.
呃  法官大人  我希望把询问奇利先生的权利
Emm... your honer
交给我的合伙人鲁迪贝勒
of Mr. Keeley over to my partner Rudy Baylor.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
你还没有执照呢
You don't have a license.
我有的选吗  你干嘛去了
I didn't have a choice. What are you doing?
你迟到了
You're late.
早上好  法官大人
Good morning, your honor.
对不起  我来晚了
Sorry I'm late, sir.
请求上前询问证人  法官大人
Approach the witness, your honor?
批准
You may.
这是杰琪莱曼切克给我的理赔手册
This is the claims manual
窃取的文件不足为凭
that was given to me by Jackie Lemancyzk.
反对有效
Obj...
我们可以上前说话吗
May we approach?
我想这个问题已经裁定了  法官大人
I thought this matter was already settled, your honor.
法官大人  我刚找到了一个
Your honor, I just this morning found a case that is controlled
类似案例
in this factual situation.
是什么
What do you have?
如果你看看这个判决
If you'll just take a look at this ruling.
是关于卡尔曼德索托和红宝石俱乐部的案子
It's Club Ruby vs. Carmine De Soto.
我给您和德拉门德先生都复印了一份
Copy for your honor and one for Mr. Drummond.
585号案  西南部第二上诉法庭  第431页
Number 585, southwest second, page 431,
由布鲁泽  不  由小莱曼斯通事务所辩护
argued by Bruiser-- by J. Lyman Stone.
这里面清楚地表明
And it shows very clearly
窃取而得的文件  事实上  是可以接受的
that stolen documents are, in fact, admissible
只要该文件并非由律师窃取的即可
if the lawyers played no part in the theft.
嗯  根据这个案例
Well, according to these head notes,
你的反对无效
this case will overrule your objection.
对不起  立奥
Sorry, Leo.
好吧  我想你是对的  法官大人
Oh, I'm sure you are, your honor.
但请记录下来我对此强烈反对
But note my strong objection.
你的反对已经被记录了
Objection noted.
我可以上前询问了吗
May I approach?
可以
Do so.
呃  法官大人嗯
Uh...Your honor...
法官大人  我很抱歉
Your honor, I'm sorry.
对不起  让您久等了  奇利先生
Excuse the interruption, Mr. Keeley.
我们得谈谈这个
We were about to talk about
巨大福利保险公司的理赔手册
the Great Benefit claims manual.
这是一份完整的手册吗  先生
Is that a complete Great Benefit claims manual, sir?
是的
Yes.
其中有第U项吗
Does it have a section "U"?
是的
It has a section "U" in it.
那我们谈谈这个神秘的第U项  好不好
Well, let's talk about this mysterious section "U."
你干嘛不向陪审团解释一下呢
Why don't we explain it to the jury?
我们来看一看
Take a look at it.
请读出第三段
Just read paragraph 3.
理赔审核员应该在接到任何申请三日内
"Claim handlers are directed to deny all claims
毫无例外地  拒绝赔付
"within 3 days of receipt of claim. No exceptions."
你怎么解释这第U项
Now, how do you explain this section "U"?
这个嘛  我们有时会收到一些
Well, sometimes we get some frivolous
无意义和虚假的索赔
and fraudulent claims in our business,
有时  我们用这一方法
and sometimes we have to use this kind of language
使我们可以更关注那些
to focus in on the legitimate
合法和必需的赔付
and more needy claims.
奇利先生  你真的认为本法庭
Mr. Keeley, do you honestly expect this court
会相信你这个解释吗
to believe that explanation?
这一段不过是段
Well, this chapter merely denotes
内部处理指示而已
in-house processing guidelines.
内部处理指示
In-house processing guidelines.
不  奇利先生  事实并非如此
No, Mr. Keeley. No, it does not.
第U项所作的远不只如此而已
Section "U" does a lot more than that.
孩子  我可不这么认为
I don't think it does that, son.
奇利先生  这里面是不是很明确的指出了
Mr. Keeley, doesn't it explain precisely
申请应该怎么被传递  推诿  再传递
how claims should be routed and shuffled and rerouted,
用尽各种方法  就是为了拒绝赔付
anything to avoid payment?
法官大人  请求上前询问证人
your honer...
批准
You may.
那么  奇利先生
Now, Mr. Keeley,
在1995年  巨大福利公司有多少份保单生效
how many policies did Great Benefit have in effect in the year 1995?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们来看看怎么样
Well, let's see.
9万8千份  这个数字是否正确
Does the figure 98,000 sound correct, give or take a few?
差不多吧
Maybe.
可能就是这么多  是的
That could be right, yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
好  那么在这些保单中  有多少人提出了索赔
Now, of these policies, how many claims were filed?
这个  这我不知道
Well, I don't-- I don't know that.
1万1千4  对不对
Does the figure of 11,400 sound correct to you,
多还是少了
give or take a few?
可能对吧
That's about right,
但是  我得确认一下才行
but I'd have to verify it, of course.
哦  我懂了  就是说我要的信息
I see. So the information that I want
都在那本书里了
is right there in that book?
那你可不可以告诉陪审团
So...
在这1万1千多份索赔申请中
of the 11 some odd thousand claims filed,
有多少份被拒绝了
how many were denied?
我可能找不到  这需要更多时间
I don't think I could. That would take more time.
奇利先生  你已经找了两个月了
You've had 2 months, Mr. Keeley.
现在回答这个问题
Now answer the question.
这个  我
Well, I...
我觉得
I don't think...
嗯
Mmm...
9141件
"9,141."
11462份理赔申请
11,462 filed.
9141份被拒赔
9,141 denied.
法官大人
Your honor...
我还有一份文件
I have yet another document.
这是巨大福利保险公司医学委员会
This is a report
提供的一份报告
from Great Benefit's medical committee.
依照先例  请求将此文件
Request permission under previous precedent
呈送给奇利先生
to present it to Mr. Keeley.
反对  同样的理由  法官大人
Same objection, your honor.
反对无效  不过记录下这一反对
Overruled. Objection noted.
谢谢你
Thank you.
呃  奇利先生  这是巨大福利保险公司嗯
Uh, Mr. Keeley, that is a report
自己的医学委员会写的报告
from Great Benefit's own medical committee,
而你是这个委员会的主席
which you chaired.
请你从第18行读起好吗
Would you please read from line 18?
由于骨髓移植
"Since bone-marrow transplants
已经成为标准治疗方式
"have become standard procedure,
巨大福利公司投资骨髓临床治疗的决定
"Great Benefit would be financially justified
将是有利可图的
in investing in bone-marrow clinics."
请求上前询问证人  法官大人
Approach the witness, your honor?
批准
You may.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看到了
There you go.
再读大声一点
A little louder.
反对  法官大人  无意义重复
Objection, your honor. Repetitious.
反对无效
Overruled.
我希望陪审团成员都能听到这些
I want the jury to hear this.
由于骨髓移植
"Since bone-marrow transplants
已经成为标准治疗方式
"have become standard procedure,
巨大福利公司投资骨髓临床治疗的决定
"Great Benefit would be financially justified
将是有利可图的
in investing in bone-marrow clinics."
有利可图
Financially justified.
这就是巨大福利公司的真相  是吧
That's what it's all about at Great Benefit, isn't it?
我问完了
Tender the witness.
德拉门德先生
Mr. Drummond.
没有问题  但是我们坚持反对意见
No questions. We rest on our objections.
你可以下去了  奇利先生
You're excused, Mr. Keeley.
谢谢
Thank you.
快点  起床了  快点  到时间了
Come on. Get up. Come on. It's time.
快点  快点
Let's go. Come on, come on.
赔付1000万美元意味着什么呢
What will giving a judgment of $10 million accomplish?
所有的保险公司都会提高售保门槛
All insurance company premiums will spin out of reach,
这将造成
and it will pave the way
政府垄断医疗保险的局面
for government-controlled health coverage.
陪审团成员们  你们的职责重大
Yours is a grave responsibility.
要明智
Be wise,
要谨慎
be careful,
要公正
and be just.
公正地作出判决
Be just.
谢谢你  法官大人
Thank you, your honor.
贝勒先生  你可以作结案陈词了
Mr. Baylor, your rebuttal.
谢谢你  法官大人
Thank you, your honor.
陪审团的女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
每当我想起丹尼雷布莱克
When I think of Donny Ray Black...
呼出最后一口气  慢慢死去的时候
Gasping for his last breath of air and slowly dying...
我就痛恨自己
I am disgusted with myself...
我学了这么多法律
And with the entire legal profession
但却无法挽救他
that could not save him.
我觉得我是个不称职的律师
I don't even feel good enough about myself as a lawyer
我没有资格作这个结案陈词
to make my own summation.
所以  我希望由丹尼雷来做
So I thought I'd... I'd let Donny Ray do that.
请展示16号证物
It's exhibit 16.
我现在体重110磅
I weigh 110 pounds.
而11个月前  我还重160磅
11 months ago, I weighed 160.
我的白血病确诊很久了
The leukemia was detected in plenty of time.
我在医院治疗的时候
I was in the hospital being treated
医生发现
when the doctors realized
唯一可以挽救我的生命的
that the only thing that could save my life
就是骨髓移植
would be a bone-marrow transplant.
可我只能出院
So, I got released from the hospital,
因为我家无力承担
'cause my family couldn't afford to pay
-这笔费用  -为什么
the bill for what they had recommended. Why?
-巨大福利保险公司拒绝了我们的理赔请求  -过来吧
Great Benefit insurance denied our claim. Come on.
没事
It's OK.
如果我能接受骨髓移植
If I had had a bone-marrow transplant,
我有90％的机会存活下来
I would have had a 90% chance of living.
我希望你们和我一样感到震惊
I hope that you are astonished... As I am,
在被告这样一家财力雄厚的大公司
at the lengths to which a wealthy insurance company,
的长期运作中
like the defendant,
他们一直从低收入家庭中吸金
will go to take money from a low-income family
通过拒赔合理的赔付请求  把钱据为己有
and then keep it by denying a legitimate claim.
难怪他们请得起那么贵的律师
It's no wonder they spend so much money on their lawyers
花重金游说和公关
and their lobbyists and their public relations machine
来让我们相信  法律需要改革
to convince us we need tort reform,
需要停止惩罚性的赔偿
that we need to put an end to punitive damages.
在此  我恳求陪审团
I'm asking you, the jury...
作出
Just...
你们内心深处  认为正确的决定
Do what you think is right in your hearts.
如果你们不对巨大福利保险公司作出惩罚
If you don't punish Great Benefit...
你们可能就是下一个受害者
You could be their next victim.
我说完了
That's it.
别紧张
don't be nervous.
陪审团有结论了吗
Has the jury reached a verdict?
是的  我们已经作出结论了  法官大人
Yes, we have, your honor.
你们已经按我的要求  写在纸上了么
Is it written on paper, according to my instructions?
是的
Yes, sir.
请读出你们的结论
Please read the verdict.
我们陪审团  认为原告方
"We, the jury, find for the plaintiff
应被赔偿  实际损失
"and award actual damages
15万美元
in the amount of $150,000."
并且  我们陪审团  认为被告方
"And we, the jury, find for the plaintiff
应付与原告  惩罚性赔偿
"and award punitive damages
5000万美元
in the amount of $50 million."
全体起立
All rise.
这些人试图隐瞒事实
These people were trying to hide things
逃避责任
and trying to get away with something they were, uh...
最后他们都被抓到了
And they got caught at it.
更引人注目的是
Another remarkable part of the story--
这个案子的主律师  鲁迪贝勒
the lead attorney on the case Rudy Baylor
这是他主打的第一场案子
was trying his first case.
不管从什么人的观点来看
That's a staggering verdict,
这都是个惊人的判决
I think, by anybody's estimation.
这肯定是金额最高的
It's certainly one of the largest...
呵呵  我的小帮工干的不错嘛
Well, not bad for a yard boy.
其实  这没什么难的
Well, it wasn't that difficult, really.
我们只是有个很好的陪审团
We just had a great jury is what we had,
然后事实纷纷出现
and the facts just fell into place.
5000万美元的惩罚性赔偿
$50 million in punitive damages.
5000万美元
$50 million?
是的
Yeah.
你能挣多少
How much do you get?
你快抓住重点了  是吧
You get right to the point, don't you?
对不起  我不是这个意思
I'm sorry. It's not what I meant.
我知道你不是这个意思的
I know you didn't.
我们能拿三分之一  不过钱还没有到帐
We get 1/3, but the money's not in the bank yet.
待会见
I'll see you later.
你就把这女孩这么一个人扔在这
You gonna leave this girl all alone?
不会很久的
Not for long.
鲁迪  鲁迪
Rudy. Rudy.
我打算把你列入我的遗产名单
I've decided I'm gonna put your name in my will.
真的  你真是哦
Oh. You know what?
你真是对我太好了  伯迪夫人
You are just too kind to me, Miss Birdie.
热点新闻
Hot off the newswire.
维尔佛莱德奇利先生  巨大福利公司首席执行官
"Mr. Wilfred Keeley, CEO of Great Benefit,
昨天下午在肯尼迪国际机场被捕
"was detained yesterday afternoon at JFK
他当时正登上一架去伦敦的飞机
"just after boarding a flight bound for Heathrow.
和她夫人一起
"Traveling with his wife,
他们说是去度假
"they claimed to be sneaking away for a quick holiday.
但是他们却无法说出
"However, they could not produce the name of a hotel anywhere in Europe..."
他们打算去的欧洲旅店的名字
At which they were expected.
今天下午5时  巨大福利保险公司
At 5 P.M. today, insurance company Great Benefit
依据破产法
filed for protection under the bankruptcy code
在克立夫兰联邦法庭提出破产保护
in federal court in Cleveland.
多个州政府正在调查巨大福利  公司
Many states are now investigating Great Benefit,
还有很多连锁赔偿案已经被提起诉讼
and a number of class-action lawsuits have been filed.
鲁迪  我是立奥德拉门德
Ludy...
看来整个公司已经被洗劫一空了
It appears the company's been looted.
我很抱歉  鲁迪
I'm--I'm sorry, Rudy.
我希望你能拿到你的那份
I wanted you to get every penny of that money.
这场官司没人赚到便宜
Everybody loses on this one.
我想让你知道
Wanted you to know.
,谢谢你  德拉门德先生
Thank you, Mr. Drummond.
巨大福利公司就像是个坏了的赌博机
Great Benefit's like a bad slot machine--
从不吐钱
never pays off.
我们要是拿那17万5就好啦
We should have taken 175,000.
我们到底在想什么
What the hell were we thinking?
这事简直乱套了  是不是
It just got all twisted, didn't it?
这种法律
This legal profession.
美国的每个律师  现在都在谈论我
Every lawyer in America is talking about me right now,
但这些却没有让我觉得
but that doesn't exactly make me feel
自己已经是法律事业的一员了
like a member of the legal community.
如果我全身心的投入工作
I might be able to go on practicing law
我可能能继续从事法律工作
if I was working with my whole heart,
但是这样我没法照顾凯莉
but I can't do that and cover Kelly.
而她现在需要非常多的照顾
And she's gonna need a lot of cover for a while.
所以尽管我还是热爱法律  我会永远热爱它
I still love the law. I'll always love it,
也许我可以去教法律
but maybe I should be teaching it
而不是做律师
instead of practicing it out here in the world.
我需要时间搞定这事
I need time to work it out.
巨大福利公司现在一文不名
Great Benefit has gone belly up.
这曾经好像天上掉下的馅饼
Barring a miracle way off in the distance,
但是现在我们一分钱也没捞到
we won't get a dime.
天啊
God.
你让他们破产了
You've put them out of business, Dot.
田纳西孟菲斯的一个小女人
One little woman from Memphis, Tennessee,
就把这群混蛋弄破产了
bankrupted them sons of bitches?
哦
Oh.
我明天会去丹尼雷的墓前
I'm gonna go to Donny Ray's grave tomorrow
告诉他这个事情
and tell him all about it.
哦  凯莉和我大概
So, I guess Kelly and I
明天一早就要走了
will be taking off first thing in the morning.
我们创造了历史  鲁迪
We made history, Rudy.
你知道吗
You know that?
我们可以吹牛一辈子了
We can always brag.
再见
Bye.
毫无疑问我已经达到了事业的顶峰
There's no doubt about it--I'm hot.
事实上  由于这个案子把我送到顶峰
In fact, I'm so hot after this case,
以后怎么走都是下坡路了
there's no place for me to go but down.
再见
See ya.
我以后碰到的每一个客户都会期盼
Every client I ever have will expect this--
这种奇迹  一点都不能少
the same magic, nothing less.
也许我确实做得到
And I could probably give it to them,
如果我不择手段
if it didn't matter how I did it.
但是那样的话  有个早上当我醒来
And then one morning,
我会发现自己已经变成了立奥德拉门德
I'd wake up and find that I'd become Leo Drummond.
嘿  你通过律考以后给我个电话  好吗
Now, you give me a call when you pass the bar exam.
没问题  小菜一碟
Yeah, piece of cake!
每个律师都至少会在某个案子中
Every lawyer, at least once in every case,
发现自己越过了  自己不愿越过的界线
feels himself crossing a line he doesn't really mean to cross.
事情就是这样
It just happens.
如果你一次又一次地跨越界线
And if you cross it enough times,
你会发现界线不存在了
it disappears forever.
而这时的你  什么都不是  只不过是个律师笑话
And then you're nothing but another lawyer joke,
只不过  是脏水中的又一条鲨鱼
just another shark in the dirty water.